<InteractionTypes>
    <Items>
        <Item>
            <Code>EBSR</Code>
            <Label>Evidence-Based Selected Response</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[<p>EBSR items combine two sets of stems and response options into a single item. Unlike
              MultipleChoice and Multi-Select item types, EBSR items cannot be displayed in horizontal or
              stacked layouts. EBSR items can only display response options vertically.</p>
              
              <p>For Smarter Balanced, the first part of an EBSR item is multiple choice where only one
              answer can be selected. In the second part, multiple answers may be selected though the
              instructions may specify a limit to the student. In the example below, the student is only
              expected to select one answer from the second part.</p>]]>
            </Description>
			      <Order>1</Order>
        </Item>
            <Item>
            <Code>EQ</Code>
            <Label>Equation</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[The Equation item response area consists of one or more entry boxes and an on-screen key
              panel containing mathematical characters. These items are 769 pixels wide or use 100% of
              the available response area width (whichever is smaller). The default height is 254 pixels.
              The item indicates which of 11 pre-defined layouts should be used for the math input key
              panel.]]>
            </Description>
            <Order>2</Order>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Code>ER</Code>
            <Label>Extended Response</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[The response areas for Extended Response (ER) and Short Answer (SA) item types essentially
              have the same appearance. Extended Response (ER) areas accommodate more text than
              Short Answer response areas. You can configure the character limit for both item types.]]>
            </Description>
            <Order>3</Order>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Code>SA</Code>
            <Label>Short Answer</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[The response areas for Extended Response (ER) and Short Answer (SA) item types essentially
              have the same appearance. Extended Response (ER) areas accommodate more text than
              Short Answer response areas. You can configure the character limit for both item types.]]>
            </Description>
			      <Order>4</Order>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Code>GI</Code>
            <Label>Grid Item</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[<p>Smarter Balanced uses three variations of the Grid Item type, each with a distinct
              appearance and interaction mode.</p>
              
              <p>The Grid Item - Graphing variant response area consists of a grid in which students plot
              points and/or lines. The available tools include a select, delete, add point, and connect line.
              Depending on the item, the point or line tool may not appear. A text box below the grid offers
              hints on what the student can do with each tool. The response area may have a background image on which the student plots points or lines
              as in this example. Grid Item – Graphing Variants may constrain points and lines; for example they may be
              constrained to a number line. The background, whether a simple grid, a graph with axes, or
              another image is simply a bitmap.</p>
              
              <p>The Grid Item – Hot Spot Variant response area consists of a space in which images are
              displayed. Clicking on certain hot spot areas causes images appear or disappear.
              Transparent sections of the images allow the background to show through.</p>
              
              <p>The Grid Item – Drag and Drop variant has a workspace with a background image. Other
              images can be dragged and dropped into the workspace. The drop locations may or may not
              be constrained. When they are constrained, dropped images snap to nearby locaitons.</p>]]>
            </Description>
            <Order>5</Order>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Code>HTQ</Code>
            <Label>Hot Text</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[The response area for Hot Text items consists of a section of text containing interactive
              words or phrases that students can either select (highlight) by clicking or rearrange by
              clicking and dragging.]]>
            </Description>
			      <Order>6</Order>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Code>MC</Code>
            <Label>Multiple Choice</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[For multiple choice responses, only one answer can be selected among several possibilities.]]> 
            </Description>
			<Order>7</Order>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Code>MS</Code>
            <Label>Multi Select</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[For the Multi Select (MS) option, students are given a number of items to select to answer
              the questions. For the example below, two of the listed items will be selected.]]>
            </Description>
			<Order>8</Order>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Code>MI</Code>
            <Label>Matching Item</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[For the Match Interaction (MI) types, text or images in rows are matched values in columns.
              The student selects the boxes where a match is valid.]]>
            </Description>
			<Order>9</Order>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Code>TI</Code>
            <Label>Table Item</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[For Table Interaction (TI) item types, students are provided with a table that includes a
              separate area of cells in which students may enter text.]]>
            </Description>
			<Order>10</Order>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Code>WER</Code>
            <Label>Writing Extended Response</Label>
            <Description>
              <![CDATA[Writing Extended Response (WER) item types provide more space for students to provide a
              longer written response. It also includes text formatting tools – bold, underline, italic,
              numbered and bulleted lists, indentation, clipboard, undo, redo, and spell checking.]]>
            </Description>
			<Order>11</Order>
        </Item>
    </Items>

    <Families>
        <Family>
            <SubjectCode>ELA</SubjectCode>
            <InteractionTypeCodes>
				<Code>EBSR</Code>
				<Code>ER</Code>
				<Code>SA</Code>
				<Code>HTQ</Code>
				<Code>MC</Code>
				<Code>MS</Code>
				<Code>MI</Code>
				<Code>WER</Code>
            </InteractionTypeCodes>
        </Family>

        <Family>
            <SubjectCode>MATH</SubjectCode>
            <InteractionTypeCodes>
				<Code>EQ</Code>
				<Code>GI</Code>
				<Code>MC</Code>
				<Code>MI</Code>
				<Code>MS</Code>
				<Code>TI</Code>
				<Code>ER</Code>
				<Code>SA</Code>
            </InteractionTypeCodes>
        </Family>
    </Families>
</InteractionTypes>