<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<root>
		<row>
		<ItemId>206</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Fluently add and subtract within 1000 using strategies and algorithms based on place value, properties of operations, and/or the relationship between addition and subtraction. Use the four operations to solve word problems involving distances, intervals of time, liquid volumes, masses of objects, and money, including problems involving simple fractions or decimals, and problems that require expressing measurements given in a larger unit in terms of a smaller unit. Represent measurement quantities using diagrams such as number line diagrams that feature a measurement scale.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>210</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve multistep word problems posed with whole numbers and having whole-number answers using the four operations, including problems in which remainders must be interpreted. Represent these problems using equations with a letter standing for the unknown quantity. Assess the reasonableness of answers using mental computation and estimation strategies including rounding.,Use the four operations to solve word problems involving distances, intervals of time, liquid volumes, masses of objects, and money, including problems involving simple fractions or decimals, and problems that require expressing measurements given in a larger unit in terms of a smaller unit. Represent measurement quantities using diagrams such as number line diagrams that feature a measurement scale.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>214</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve multistep word problems posed with whole numbers and having whole-number answers using the four operations, including problems in which remainders must be interpreted. Represent these problems using equations with a letter standing for the unknown quantity. Assess the reasonableness of answers using mental computation and estimation strategies including rounding. Use the four operations to solve word problems involving distances, intervals of time, liquid volumes, masses of objects, and money, including problems involving simple fractions or decimals, and problems that require expressing measurements given in a larger unit in terms of a smaller unit. Represent measurement quantities using diagrams such as number line diagrams that feature a measurement scale.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>217</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve multistep word problems posed with whole numbers and having whole-number answers using the four operations, including problems in which remainders must be interpreted. Represent these problems using equations with a letter standing for the unknown quantity. Assess the reasonableness of answers using mental computation and estimation strategies including rounding.,Use the four operations to solve word problems involving distances, intervals of time, liquid volumes, masses of objects, and money, including problems involving simple fractions or decimals, and problems that require expressing measurements given in a larger unit in terms of a smaller unit. Represent measurement quantities using diagrams such as number line diagrams that feature a measurement scale.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1431</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Create equations in two variables to represent relationships between quantities; graph equations on coordinate axes with labels and scales.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1432</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve linear equations and inequalities in one variable, including equations with coefficients represented by letters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1434</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Graph square root, cube root, and piecewise-defined functions, including step functions and absolute value functions.ok</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1435</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Fit a linear function for a scatter plot that suggests a linear association.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1436</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Create equations in two variables to represent relationships between quantities; graph equations on coordinate axes with labels and scales.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1437</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Create equations in two variables to represent relationships between quantities; graph equations on coordinate axes with labels and scales.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1444</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Create equations in two variables to represent relationships between quantities; graph equations on coordinate axes with labels and scales.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1463</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent three-dimensional figures using nets made up of rectangles and triangles, and use the nets to find the surface area of these figures. Apply these techniques in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1468</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find the volume of a right rectangular prism with fractional edge lengths by packing it with unit cubes of the appropriate unit fraction edge lengths, and show that the volume is the same as would be found by multiplying the edge lengths of the prism. Apply the formulas V = l w h and V = b h to find volumes of right rectangular prisms with fractional edge lengths in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1470</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent three-dimensional figures using nets made up of rectangles and triangles, and use the nets to find the surface area of these figures. Apply these techniques in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1472</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Construct, autonomously, chains of reasoning that will justify or refute propositions or conjectures.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find the volume of a right rectangular prism with fractional edge lengths by packing it with unit cubes of the appropriate unit fraction edge lengths, and show that the volume is the same as would be found by multiplying the edge lengths of the prism. Apply the formulas V = l w h and V = b h to find volumes of right rectangular prisms with fractional edge lengths in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1478</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent three-dimensional figures using nets made up of rectangles and triangles, and use the nets to find the surface area of these figures. Apply these techniques in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1490</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply the area and perimeter formulas for rectangles in real world and mathematical problems. For example, find the width of a rectangular room given the area of the flooring and the length, by viewing the area formula as a multiplication equation with an unknown factor.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1491</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve word problems involving addition and subtraction of fractions referring to the same whole, including cases of unlike denominators, e.g., by using visual fraction models or equations to represent the problem. Use benchmark fractions and number sense of fractions to estimate mentally and assess the reasonableness of answers. For example, recognize an incorrect result 2/5 + 1/2 = 3/7, by observing that 3/7 &lt; 1/2.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1492</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Add and subtract fractions with unlike denominators (including mixed numbers) by replacing given fractions with equivalent fractions in such a way as to produce an equivalent sum or difference of fractions with like denominators. For example, 2/3 + 5/4 = 8/12 + 15/12 = 23/12. (In general, a/b + c/d = (ad + bc)/bd.) Apply and extend previous understandings of multiplication to multiply a fraction or whole number by a fraction. A) Interpret the product (a/b) × q as a parts of a partition of q into b equal parts; equivalently, as the result of a sequence of operations a × q ÷ b. For example, use a visual fraction model to show (2/3) × 4 = 8/3, and create a story context for this equation. Do the same with (2/3) × (4/5) = 8/15. (In general, (a/b) × (c/d) = ac/bd.) Understand a fraction a/b with a &gt; 1 as a sum of fractions 1/b. D) Solve word problems involving addition and subtraction of fractions referring to the same whole and having like denominators, e.g., by using visual fraction models and equations to represent the problem.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1493</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>State logical assumptions being used.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1505</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Know that straight lines are widely used to model relationships between two quantitative variables. For scatter plots that suggest a linear association, informally fit a straight line, and informally assess the model fit by judging the closeness of the data points to the line.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1506</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Construct a function to model a linear relationship between two quantities. Determine the rate of change and initial value of the function from a description of a relationship or from two (x, y) values, including reading these from a table or from a graph. Interpret the rate of change and initial value of a linear function in terms of the situation it models, and in terms of its graph or a table of values.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1507</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use the equation of a linear model to solve problems in the context of bivariate measurement data, interpreting the slope and intercept. For example, in a linear model for a biology experiment, interpret a slope of 1.5 cm/hr as meaning that an additional hour of sunlight each day is associated with an additional 1.5 cm in mature plant height.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1518</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use variables to represent quantities in a real-world or mathematical problem, and construct simple equations and inequalities to solve problems by reasoning about the quantities. A) Solve word problems leading to equations of the form px + q = r and p(x + q) = r, where p, q, and r are specific rational numbers. Solve equations of these forms fluently. Compare an algebraic solution to an arithmetic solution, identifying the sequence of the operations used in each approach. For example, the perimeter of a rectangle is 54 cm. Its length is 6 cm. What is its width?</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1519</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Base arguments on concrete referents such as objects, drawings, diagrams, and actions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Construct and interpret scatter plots for bivariate measurement data to investigate patterns of association between two quantities. Describe patterns such as clustering, outliers, positive or negative association, linear association, and nonlinear association.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1574</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1576</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw a scaled picture graph and a scaled bar graph to represent a data set with several categories. Solve one- and two-step “how many more” and “how many less” problems using information presented in scaled bar graphs. For example, draw a bar graph in which each square in the bar graph might represent 5 pets.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1578</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw a scaled picture graph and a scaled bar graph to represent a data set with several categories. Solve one- and two-step “how many more” and “how many less” problems using information presented in scaled bar graphs. For example, draw a bar graph in which each square in the bar graph might represent 5 pets. Solve real world and mathematical problems involving perimeters of polygons, including finding the perimeter given the side lengths, finding an unknown side length, and exhibiting rectangles with the same perimeter and different areas or with the same area and different perimeters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1598</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply the area and perimeter formulas for rectangles in real world and mathematical problems. For example, find the width of a rectangular room given the area of the flooring and the length, by viewing the area formula as a multiplication equation with an unknown factor.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
		<BrailleCopiedId>1490</BrailleCopiedId>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1599</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Interpret functions that arise in applications in terms of the context.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
		<BrailleCopiedId>1484</BrailleCopiedId>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1600</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Fit a linear function for a scatter plot that suggests a linear association.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1601</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Know that straight lines are widely used to model relationships between two quantitative variables. For scatter plots that suggest a linear association, informally fit a straight line, and informally assess the model fit by judging the closeness of the data points to the line.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
		<BrailleCopiedId>1505</BrailleCopiedId>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1609</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent three-dimensional figures using nets made up of rectangles and triangles, and use the nets to find the surface area of these figures. Apply these techniques in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
		<BrailleCopiedId>1463</BrailleCopiedId>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>1610</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw a scaled picture graph and a scaled bar graph to represent a data set with several categories. Solve one- and two-step “how many more” and “how many less” problems using information presented in scaled bar graphs. For example, draw a bar graph in which each square in the bar graph might represent 5 pets. Solve real world and mathematical problems involving perimeters of polygons, including finding the perimeter given the side lengths, finding an unknown side length, and exhibiting rectangles with the same perimeter and different areas or with the same area and different perimeters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
		<BrailleCopiedId>1578</BrailleCopiedId>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2059</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use proportional relationships to solve multistep ratio and percent problems. Examples: simple interest, tax, markups and markdowns, gratuities and commissions, fees, percent increase and decrease, percent error.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2060</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compute unit rates associated with ratios of fractions, including ratios of lengths, areas and other quantities measured in like or different units. For example, if a person walks 1/2 mile in each 1/4 hour, compute the unit rate as the complex fraction 1/2 / 1/4 miles per hour, equivalently 2 miles per hour.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2061</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use proportional relationships to solve multistep ratio and percent problems. Examples: simple interest, tax, markups and markdowns, gratuities and commissions, fees, percent increase and decrease, percent error.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2062</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use proportional relationships to solve multistep ratio and percent problems. Examples: simple interest, tax, markups and markdowns, gratuities and commissions, fees, percent increase and decrease, percent error.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2063</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>State logical assumptions being used.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use proportional relationships to solve multistep ratio and percent problems. Examples: simple interest, tax, markups and markdowns, gratuities and commissions, fees, percent increase and decrease, percent error.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2064</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Base arguments on concrete referents such as objects, drawings, diagrams, and actions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand the concept of a ratio and use ratio language to describe a ratio relationship between two quantities. For example, “The ratio of wings to beaks in the bird house at the zoo was 2:1, because for every 2 wings there was 1 beak.” “For every vote candidate A received, candidate C received nearly three votes.”</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2788</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw a scaled picture graph and a scaled bar graph to represent a data set with several categories. Solve one- and two-step “how many more” and “how many less” problems using information presented in scaled bar graphs. For example, draw a bar graph in which each square in the bar graph might represent 5 pets.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>TI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2789</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw a scaled picture graph and a scaled bar graph to represent a data set with several categories. Solve one- and two-step “how many more” and “how many less” problems using information presented in scaled bar graphs. For example, draw a bar graph in which each square in the bar graph might represent 5 pets.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>TI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2790</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Identify important quantities in a practical situation and map their relationships (e.g., using diagrams, two-way tables, graphs, flowcharts, or formulas). (DOK 1, 2, 3)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve multistep word problems posed with whole numbers and having whole-number answers using the four operations, including problems in which remainders must be interpreted. Represent these problems using equations with a letter standing for the unknown quantity. Assess the reasonableness of answers using mental computation and estimation strategies including rounding. Use the four operations to solve word problems involving distances, intervals of time, liquid volumes, masses of objects, and money, including problems involving simple fractions or decimals, and problems that require expressing measurements given in a larger unit in terms of a smaller unit. Represent measurement quantities using diagrams such as number line diagrams that feature a measurement scale.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>TI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3200</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use equivalent fractions as a strategy to add and subtract fractions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Add and subtract fractions with unlike denominators (including mixed numbers) by replacing given fractions with equivalent fractions in such a way as to produce an equivalent sum or difference of fractions with like denominators. For example, 2/3 + 5/4 = 8/12 + 15/12 = 23/12. (In general, a/b + c/d = (ad + bc)/bd.)</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3202</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>L</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Functions: Interpret functions that arise in applications in terms of the context.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Calculate and interpret the average rate of change of a function (presented symbolically or as a table) over a specified interval. Estimate the rate of change from a graph.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3204</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand ratio concepts and use ratio reasoning to solve problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find a percent of a quantity as a rate per 100 (e.g., 30% of a quantity means 30/100 times the quantity); solve problems involving finding the whole, given a part and the percent.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3206</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Reason about and solve one-variable equations and inequalities.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve real-world and mathematical problems by writing and solving equations of the form x + p = q and px = q for cases in which p, q and x are all nonnegative rational numbers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3208</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand the connections between proportional relationships, lines, and linear equations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use similar triangles to explain why the slope m is the same between any two distinct points on a non-vertical line in the coordinate plane; derive the equation y = mx for a line through the origin and the equation y = mx + b for a line intercepting the vertical axis at b.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3210</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Represent and solve problems involving multiplication and division.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the unknown whole number in a multiplication or division equation relating three whole numbers. For example, determine the unknown number that makes the equation true in each of the equations 8 × ? = 48, 5 = ?? ÷ 3, 6 × 6 = ?.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3212</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Develop understanding of fractions as numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Express whole numbers as fractions, and recognize fractions that are equivalent to whole numbers. Examples: Express 3 in the form 3 = 3/1; recognize that 6/1 = 6; locate 4/4 and 1 at the same point of a number line diagram.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3214</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve real world problems involving division of unit fractions by non-zero whole numbers and division of whole numbers by unit fractions, e.g., by using visual fraction models and equations to represent the problem. For example, how much chocolate will each person get if 3 people share 1/2 lb of chocolate equally? How many 1/3-cup servings are in 2 cups of raisins?</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3216</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Make a line plot to display a data set of measurements in fractions of a unit (1/2, 1/4, 1/8). Solve problems involving addition and subtraction of fractions by using information presented in line plots. For example, from a line plot find and interpret the difference in length between the longest and shortest specimens in an insect collection.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3218</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve word problems involving addition and subtraction of fractions referring to the same whole, including cases of unlike denominators, e.g., by using visual fraction models or equations to represent the problem. Use benchmark fractions and number sense of fractions to estimate mentally and assess the reasonableness of answers. For example, recognize an incorrect result 2/5 + 1/2 = 3/7, by observing that 3/7 &lt; 1/2.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3220</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>P</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Statistics and Probability: Summarize, represent, and interpret data on a single count or measurement variable.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent data with plots on the real number line (dot plots, histograms, and box plots).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3222</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve two-step word problems using the four operations. Represent these problems using equations with a letter standing for the unknown quantity. Assess the reasonableness of answers using mental computation and estimation strategies including rounding.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3224</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>J</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Algebra: Represent and solve equations and inequalities graphically.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Graph the solutions to a linear inequality in two variables as a half plane (excluding the boundary in the case of a strict inequality), and graph the solution set to a system of linear inequalities in two variables as the intersection of the corresponding half-planes.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3226</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use place value understanding and properties of operations to perform multi-digit arithmetic.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Multiply a whole number of up to four digits by a one-digit whole number, and multiply two two-digit numbers, using strategies based on place value and the properties of operations. Illustrate and explain the calculation by using equations, rectangular arrays, and/or area models.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3228</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze and solve linear equations and pairs of simultaneous linear equations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve systems of two linear equations in two variables algebraically, and estimate solutions by graphing the equations. Solve simple cases by inspection. For example, 3x + 2y = 5 and 3x + 2y = 6 have no solution because 3x + 2y cannot simultaneously be 5 and 6.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3230</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Base arguments on concrete referents such as objects, drawings, diagrams, and actions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Prove theorems about lines and angles. Theorems include: vertical angles are congruent; when a transversal crosses parallel lines, alternate interior angles are congruent and corresponding angles are congruent; points on a perpendicular bisector of a line segment are exactly those equidistant from the segment’s endpoints.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3232</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>M</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Functions: Analyze functions using different representations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Graph functions expressed symbolically and show key features of the graph, by hand in simple cases and using technology for more complicated cases.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3234</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Multiply and divide within 100.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Fluently multiply and divide within 100, using strategies such as the relationship between multiplication and division (e.g., knowing that 8 × 5 = 40, one knows 40 ÷ 5 = 8) or properties of operations. By the end of Grade 3, know from memory all products of two one-digit numbers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3236</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand ordering and absolute value of rational numbers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3238</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>J</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Graph points on the coordinate plane to solve real-world and mathematical problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent real world and mathematical problems by graphing points in the first quadrant of the coordinate plane, and interpret coordinate values of points in the context of the situation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3240</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of multiplication and division to multiply and divide fractions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Comparing the size of a product to the size of one factor on the basis of the size of the other factor, without performing the indicated multiplication.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3242</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze and solve linear equations and pairs of simultaneous linear equations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve systems of two linear equations in two variables algebraically, and estimate solutions by graphing the equations. Solve simple cases by inspection. For example, 3x + 2y = 5 and 3x + 2y = 6 have no solution because 3x + 2y cannot simultaneously be 5 and 6.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3244</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>I</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve real-world and mathematical problems involving volume of cylinders, cones, and spheres.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Know the formulas for the volumes of cones, cylinders, and spheres and use them to solve real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3246</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve problems involving the four operations, and identify and explain patterns in arithmetic.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Identify arithmetic patterns (including patterns in the addition table or multiplication table), and explain them using properties of operations. For example, observe that 4 times a number is always even, and explain why 4 times a number can be decomposed into two equal addends.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>TI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3248</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand congruence and similarity using physical models, transparencies, or geometry software.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Verify experimentally the properties of rotations, reflections, and translations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3250</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Construct a function to model a linear relationship between two quantities. Determine the rate of change and initial value of the function from a description of a relationship or from two (x, y) values, including reading these from a table or from a graph. Interpret the rate of change and initial value of a linear function in terms of the situation it models, and in terms of its graph or a table of values.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3252</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>I</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Geometric measurement: understand concepts of volume and relate volume to multiplication and to addition.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Relate volume to the operations of multiplication and addition and solve real world and mathematical problems involving volume.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3254</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Algebra: Perform arithmetic operations on polynomials.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that polynomials form a system analogous to the integers, namely, they are closed under the operations of addition, subtraction, and multiplication; add, subtract, and multiply polynomials.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3256</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>H</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve real-world and mathematical problems involving area, surface area, and volume.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find the volume of a right rectangular prism with fractional edge lengths by packing it with unit cubes of the appropriate unit fraction edge lengths, and show that the volume is the same as would be found by multiplying the edge lengths of the prism. Apply the formulas V = l w h and V = b h to find volumes of right rectangular prisms with fractional edge lengths in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3258</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>State logical assumptions being used.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent and solve problems involving multiplication and division.,Solve two-step word problems using the four operations. Represent these problems using equations with a letter standing for the unknown quantity. Assess the reasonableness of answers using mental computation and estimation strategies including rounding.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3260</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Identify important quantities in a practical situation and map their relationships (e.g., using diagrams, two-way tables, graphs, flowcharts, or formulas).</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Make a line plot to display a data set of measurements in fractions of a unit (1/2, 1/4, 1/8). Use operations on fractions for this grade to solve problems involving information presented in line plots. For example, given different measurements of liquid in identical beakers, find the amount of liquid each beaker would contain if the total amount in all the beakers were redistributed equally. Convert among different-sized standard measurement units within a given measurement system (e.g., convert 5 cm to 0.05 m), and use these conversions in solving multi-step, real world problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3262</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Compute fluently with multi-digit numbers and find common factors and multiples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Fluently divide multi-digit numbers using the standard algorithm.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3264</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of numbers to the system of rational numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve real-world and mathematical problems by graphing points in all four quadrants of the coordinate plane. Include use of coordinates and absolute value to find distances between points with the same first coordinate or the same second coordinate.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3266</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain patterns in the number of zeros of the product when multiplying a number by powers of 10, and explain patterns in the placement of the decimal point when a decimal is multiplied or divided by a power of 10. Use whole-number exponents to denote powers of 10.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3268</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw a scaled picture graph and a scaled bar graph to represent a data set with several categories. Solve one- and two-step “how many more” and “how many less” problems using information presented in scaled bar graphs. For example, draw a bar graph in which each square in the bar graph might represent 5 pets.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3270</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>N</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Functions: Build a function that models a relationship between two quantities.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write arithmetic and geometric sequences both recursively and with an explicit formula, use them to model situations, and translate between the two forms.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3272</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>H</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Algebra: Understand solving equations as a process of reasoning and explain the reasoning.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve simple rational and radical equations in one variable, and give examples showing how extraneous solutions may arise.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3274</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Interpret division of a whole number by a unit fraction, and compute such quotients. For example, create a story context for 4 ÷ (1/5), and use a visual fraction model to show the quotient. Use the relationship between multiplication and division to explain that 4 ÷ (1/5) = 20 because 20 × (1/5) = 4.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3276</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze and solve linear equations and pairs of simultaneous linear equations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3278</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>K</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Functions: Understand the concept of a function and use function notation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that a function from one set (called the domain) to another set (called the range) assigns to each element of the domain exactly one element of the range. If f is a function and x is an element of its domain, then f(x) denotes the output of f corresponding to the input x. The graph of f is the graph of the equation y = f(x).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3280</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Number and Quantities: Reason quantitatively and use units to solve problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use units as a way to understand problems and to guide the solution of multi-step problems; choose and interpret units consistently in formulas; choose and interpret the scale and the origin in graphs and data displays.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3282</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>K</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Functions: Understand the concept of a function and use function notation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recognize that sequences are functions, sometimes defined recursively, whose domain is a subset of the integers. For example, the Fibonacci sequence is defined recursively by f(0) = f(1) = 1, f(n+1) = f(n) + f(n-1) for n = 1.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3284</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Add, subtract, multiply, and divide decimals to hundredths, using concrete models or drawings and strategies based on place value, properties of operations, and/or the relationship between addition and subtraction; relate the strategy to a written method and explain the reasoning used.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3286</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Construct, autonomously, chains of reasoning that will justify or refute propositions or conjectures.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compute unit rates associated with ratios of fractions, including ratios of lengths, areas and other quantities measured in like or different units. For example, if a person walks 1/2 mile in each 1/4 hour, compute the unit rate as the complex fraction 1/2 / 1/4 miles per hour, equivalently 2 miles per hour. Use ratio and rate reasoning to solve real-world and mathematical problems, e.g., by reasoning about tables of equivalent ratios, tape diagrams, double number line diagrams, or equations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3288</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>O</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Geometry: Define trigonometric ratios and solve problems involving right triangles.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use trigonometric ratios and the Pythagorean Theorem to solve right triangles in applied problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3290</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand the place value system.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare two decimals to thousandths based on meanings of the digits in each place, using &gt;, =, and &lt; symbols to record the results of comparisons.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3292</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of multiplication and division to multiply and divide fractions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve real world problems involving multiplication of fractions and mixed numbers, e.g., by using visual fraction models or equations to represent the problem.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3294</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Algebra: Write expressions in equivalent forms to solve problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Choose and produce an equivalent form of an expression to reveal and explain properties of the quantity represented by the expression.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3296</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Algebra: Create equations that describe numbers or relationships</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Create equations and inequalities in one variable and use them to solve problems. Include equations arising from linear and quadratic functions, and simple rational and exponential functions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3298</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>H</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Algebra: Understand solving equations as a process of reasoning and explain the reasoning.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve simple rational and radical equations in one variable, and give examples showing how extraneous solutions may arise.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3300</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of operations with fractions to add, subtract, multiply, and divide rational numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that integers can be divided, provided that the divisor is not zero, and every quotient of integers (with non-zero divisor) is a rational number. If p and q are integers, then –(p/q) = (–p)/q = p/(–q). Interpret quotients of rational numbers by describing real world contexts.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3302</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use equivalent fractions as a strategy to add and subtract fractions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Add and subtract fractions with unlike denominators (including mixed numbers) by replacing given fractions with equivalent fractions in such a way as to produce an equivalent sum or difference of fractions with like denominators. For example, 2/3 + 5/4 = 8/12 + 15/12 = 23/12. (In general, a/b + c/d = (ad + bc)/bd.)</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3304</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Algebra: Interpret the structure of expressions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use the structure of an expression to identify ways to rewrite it. For example, see x4 – y4 as (x2)2 – (y2)2, thus recognizing it as a difference of squares that can be factored as (x2 – y2)(x2 + y2).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3306</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Work with radicals and integer exponents.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use square root and cube root symbols to represent solutions to equations of the form x^2 = p and x^3 = p, where p is a positive rational number. Evaluate square roots of small perfect squares and cube roots of small perfect cubes. Know that v2 is irrational.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3308</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve linear equations and inequalities in one variable, including equations with coefficients represented by letters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3310</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand the place value system.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Read and write decimals to thousandths using base-ten numerals, number names, and expanded form, e.g., 347.392 = 3 × 100 + 4 × 10 + 7 × 1 + 3 × (1/10) + 9 × (1/100) + 2 × (1/1000).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3312</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Know that there are numbers that are not rational, and approximate them by rational numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use rational approximations of irrational numbers to compare the size of irrational numbers, locate them approximately on a number line diagram, and estimate the value of expressions (e.g., p^2). For example, by truncating the decimal expansion of v2, show that v2 is between 1 and 2, then between 1.4 and 1.5, and explain how to continue on to get better approximations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3314</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze and solve linear equations and pairs of simultaneous linear equations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Give examples of linear equations in one variable with one solution, infinitely many solutions, or no solutions. Show which of these possibilities is the case by successively transforming the given equation into simpler forms, until an equivalent equation of the form x = a, a = a, or a = b results (where a and b are different numbers).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3316</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Define, evaluate, and compare functions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that a function is a rule that assigns to each input exactly one output. The graph of a function is the set of ordered pairs consisting of an input and the corresponding output.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3318</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Identify important quantities in a practical situation and map their relationships (e.g., using diagrams, two-way tables, graphs, flowcharts, or formulas).</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Create equations in two or more variables to represent relationships between quantities; graph equations on coordinate axes with labels and scales.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3320</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the technique of breaking an argument into cases.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve word problems involving addition and subtraction of fractions referring to the same whole, including cases of unlike denominators, e.g., by using visual fraction models or equations to represent the problem. Use benchmark fractions and number sense of fractions to estimate mentally and assess the reasonableness of answers. For example, recognize an incorrect result 2/5 + 1/2 = 3/7, by observing that 3/7 &lt; 1/2.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3322</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Construct, autonomously, chains of reasoning that will justify or refute propositions or conjectures.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find all factor pairs for a whole number in the range 1–100. Recognize that a whole number is a multiple of each of its factors. Determine whether a given whole number in the range 1–100 is a multiple of a given one-digit number. Determine whether a given whole number in the range 1–100 is prime or composite.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3324</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the technique of breaking an argument into cases.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain equivalence of fractions in special cases, and compare fractions by reasoning about their size.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3326</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Base arguments on concrete referents such as objects, drawings, diagrams, and actions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand ordering and absolute value of rational numbers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3328</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the technique of breaking an argument into cases.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use informal arguments to establish facts about the angle sum and exterior angle of triangles, about the angles created when parallel lines are cut by a transversal, and the angle-angle criterion for similarity of triangles. For example, arrange three copies of the same triangle so that the sum of the three angles appears to form a line, and give an argument in terms of transversals why this is so.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3332</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve unit rate problems including those involving unit pricing and constant speed. For example, if it took 7 hours to mow 4 lawns, then at that rate, how many lawns could be mowed in 35 hours? At what rate were lawns being mowed?</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3334</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve systems of equations</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3336</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand ratio concepts and use ratio reasoning to solve problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3338</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>State logical assumptions being used.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of multiplication and division.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3340</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Base arguments on concrete referents such as objects, drawings, diagrams, and actions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand properties of multiplication and the relationship between multiplication and division.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3342</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Construct, autonomously, chains of reasoning that will justify or refute propositions or conjectures.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Prove theorems about parallelograms. Theorems include: opposite sides are congruent, opposite angles are congruent, the diagonals of a parallelogram bisect each other, and conversely, rectangles are parallelograms with congruent diagonals.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3344</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Extend understanding of fractions equivalence and ordering.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare two fractions with different numerators and different denominators, e.g., by creating common denominators or numerators, or by comparing to a benchmark fraction such as 1/2. Recognize that comparisons are valid only when the two fractions refer to the same whole. Record the results of comparisons with symbols &gt;, =, or &lt;, and justify the conclusions, e.g., by using a visual fraction model.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3346</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze and solve pairs of simultaneous linear equations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3348</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>J</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Algebra: Represent and solve equations and inequalities graphically.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that the graph of an equation in two variables is the set of all its solutions plotted in the coordinate plane, often forming a curve (which could be a line).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3350</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the technique of breaking an argument into cases.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand a fraction 1/b as the quantity formed by 1 part when a whole is partitioned into b equal parts; understand a fraction a/b as the quantity formed by a parts of size 1/b.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3352</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Identify important quantities in a practical situation and map their relationships (e.g., using diagrams, two-way tables, graphs, flowcharts, or formulas). (DOK 1, 2, 3)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use trigonometric ratios and the Pythagorean Theorem to solve right triangles in applied problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3354</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Relate volume to the operations of multiplication and addition and solve real world and mathematical problems involving volume.,Use the four operations to solve word problems involving distances, intervals of time, liquid volumes, masses of objects, and money, including problems involving simple fractions or decimals, and problems that require expressing measurements given in a larger unit in terms of a smaller unit. Represent measurement quantities using diagrams such as number line diagrams that feature a measurement scale.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3356</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze proportional relationships and use them to solve real-world and mathematical problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use proportional relationships to solve multistep ratio and percent problems. Examples: simple interest, tax, markups and markdowns, gratuities and commissions, fees, percent increase and decrease, percent error.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3358</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Algebra: Create equations that describe numbers or relationships</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Create equations and inequalities in one variable and use them to solve problems. Include equations arising from linear and quadratic functions, and simple rational and exponential functions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3360</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Create equations and inequalities in one variable and use them to solve problems. Include equations arising from linear and quadratic functions, and simple rational and exponential functions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3362</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Number and Quantities: Extend the properties of exponents to rational exponents.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Rewrite expressions involving radicals and rational exponents using the properties of exponents.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3364</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Perform operations with multi-digit whole numbers and with decimals to hundredths.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3366</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>State logical assumptions being used.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Geometric measurement: understand concepts of area and relate area to multiplication and to addition.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3368</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply the formulas V = l × w × h and V = b × h for rectangular prisms to find volumes of right rectangular prisms with whole number edge lengths in the context of solving real world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3369</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand the connections between proportional relationships, lines, and linear equations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Graph proportional relationships, interpreting the unit rate as the slope of the graph. Compare two different proportional relationships represented in different ways. For example, compare a distance-time graph to a distance-time equation to determine which of two moving objects has greater speed.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3371</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>At later grades, determine conditions under which an argument does and does not apply. (For example, area increases with perimeter for squares, but not for all plane figures.)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Construct the inscribed and circumscribed circles of a triangle, and prove properties of angles for a quadrilateral inscribed in a circle.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3373</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Perform operations with multi-digit whole numbers and with decimals to hundredths.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find whole-number quotients of whole numbers with up to four-digit dividends and two-digit divisors, using strategies based on place value, the properties of operations, and/or the relationship between multiplication and division. Illustrate and explain the calculation by using equations, rectangular arrays, and/or area models.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3375</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Write and interpret numerical expressions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write and interpret numerical expressions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3377</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of multiplication and division to multiply and divide fractions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of multiplication and division.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3379</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve two-step word problems using the four operations. Represent these problems using equations with a letter standing for the unknown quantity. Assess the reasonableness of answers using mental computation and estimation strategies including rounding.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3381</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Prove theorems about parallelograms. Theorems include: opposite sides are congruent, opposite angles are congruent, the diagonals of a parallelogram bisect each other, and conversely, rectangles are parallelograms with congruent diagonals.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3383</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Know that there are numbers that are not rational, and approximate them by rational numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Know that numbers that are not rational are called irrational. Understand informally that every number has a decimal expansion; for rational numbers show that the decimal expansion repeats eventually, and convert a decimal expansion which repeats eventually into a rational number.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3385</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand congruence and similarity using physical models, transparencies, or geometry software.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Describe the effect of dilations, translations, rotations, and reflections on two-dimensional figures using coordinates.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3387</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of numbers to the system of rational numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find and position integers and other rational numbers on a horizontal or vertical number line diagram; find and position pairs of integers and other rational numbers on a coordinate plane.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3389</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Build fractions from unit fractions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3391</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Develop understanding of fractions as numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent a fraction 1/b on a number line diagram by defining the interval from 0 to 1 as the whole and partitioning it into b equal parts. Recognize that each part has size 1/b and that the endpoint of the part based at 0 locates the number 1/b on the number line.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3393</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use place value understanding and properties of operations to perform multi-digit arithmetic.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Fluently add and subtract within 1000 using strategies and algorithms based on place value, properties of operations, and/or the relationship between addition and subtraction.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3395</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use a pair of perpendicular number lines, called axes, to define a coordinate system, with the intersection of the lines (the origin) arranged to coincide with the 0 on each line and a given point in the plane located by using an ordered pair of numbers, called its coordinates. Understand that the first number indicates how far to travel from the origin in the direction of one axis, and the second number indicates how far to travel in the direction of the second axis, with the convention that the names of the two axes and the coordinates correspond (e.g., x-axis and x-coordinate, y-axis and y-coordinate).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3397</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand ratio concepts and use ratio reasoning to solve problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve unit rate problems including those involving unit pricing and constant speed. For example, if it took 7 hours to mow 4 lawns, then at that rate, how many lawns could be mowed in 35 hours? At what rate were lawns being mowed?</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3399</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>State logical assumptions being used.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw polygons in the coordinate plane given coordinates for the vertices; use coordinates to find the length of a side joining points with the same first coordinate or the same second coordinate. Apply these techniques in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems. Graph points on the coordinate plane to solve real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3401</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Identify important quantities in a practical situation and map their relationships (e.g., using diagrams, two-way tables, graphs, flowcharts, or formulas).</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use proportional relationships to solve multistep ratio and percent problems. Examples: simple interest, tax, markups and markdowns, gratuities and commissions, fees, percent increase and decrease, percent error.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3403</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve real-life and mathematical problems using numerical and algebraic expressions and equations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve word problems leading to inequalities of the form px + q &gt; r or px + q &lt; r, where p, q, and r are specific rational numbers. Graph the solution set of the inequality and interpret it in the context of the problem. For example: As a salesperson, you are paid $50 per week plus $3 per sale. This week you want your pay to be at least $100. Write an inequality for the number of sales you need to make, and describe the solutions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3405</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Represent and solve problems involving multiplication and division.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use multiplication and division within 100 to solve word problems in situations involving equal groups, arrays, and measurement quantities, e.g., by using drawings and equations with a symbol for the unknown number to represent the problem.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3407</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>H</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Represent and interpret data.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Generate measurement data by measuring lengths using rulers marked with halves and fourths of an inch. Show the data by making a line plot, where the horizontal scale is marked off in appropriate units— whole numbers, halves, or quarters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3409</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use place value understanding and properties of operations to perform multi-digit arithmetic.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find whole-number quotients and remainders with up to four-digit dividends and one-digit divisors, using strategies based on place value, the properties of operations, and/or the relationship between multiplication and division. Illustrate and explain the calculation by using equations, rectangular arrays, and/or area models.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3411</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare two fractions with different numerators and different denominators, e.g., by creating common denominators or numerators, or by comparing to a benchmark fraction such as 1/2. Recognize that comparisons are valid only when the two fractions refer to the same whole. Record the results of comparisons with symbols &gt;, =, or &lt;, and justify the conclusions, e.g., by using a visual fraction model.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3413</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Multiply a whole number of up to four digits by a one-digit whole number, and multiply two two-digit numbers, using strategies based on place value and the properties of operations. Illustrate and explain the calculation by using equations, rectangular arrays, and/or area models.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3415</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>State logical assumptions being used.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find probabilities of compound events using organized lists, tables, tree diagrams, and simulation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>TI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3417</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>K</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Reason with shapes and their attributes.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Partition shapes into parts with equal areas. Express the area of each part as a unit fraction of the whole. For example, partition a shape into 4 parts with equal area, and describe the area of each part as 1/4 of the area of the shape.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3419</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Extend understanding of fractions equivalence and ordering.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain why a fraction a/b is equivalent to a fraction (n × a)/(n × b) by using visual fraction models, with attention to how the number and size of the parts differ even though the two fractions themselves are the same size. Use this principle to recognize and generate equivalent fractions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3421</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Build fractions from unit fractions by applying and extending previous understandings of operations on whole numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand a fraction a/b with a &gt; 1 as a sum of fractions 1/b.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3423</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>H</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand decimal notation for fractions, and compare decimal fractions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use decimal notation for fractions with denominators 10 or 100. For example, rewrite 0.62 as 62/100; describe a length as 0.62 meters; locate 0.62 on a number line diagram.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3425</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>L</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Draw and identify lines and angles, and classify shapes by properties of their lines and angles.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recognize a line of symmetry for a two-dimensional figure as a line across the figure such that the figure can be folded along the line into matching parts. Identify line-symmetric figures and draw lines of symmetry.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3427</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve linear equations and inequalities in one variable, including equations with coefficients represented by letters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3429</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve linear equations and inequalities in one variable, including equations with coefficients represented by letters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3431</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Represent and solve problems involving multiplication and division.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use multiplication and division within 100 to solve word problems in situations involving equal groups, arrays, and measurement quantities, e.g., by using drawings and equations with a symbol for the unknown number to represent the problem.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3433</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Perform operations with multi-digit whole numbers and with decimals to hundredths.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Fluently multiply multi-digit whole numbers using the standard algorithm.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3435</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>K</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Geometric measurement: understand concepts of angle and measure angles.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recognize angle measure as additive. When an angle is decomposed into non-overlapping parts, the angle measure of the whole is the sum of the angle measures of the parts. Solve addition and subtraction problems to find unknown angles on a diagram in real world and mathematical problems, e.g., by using an equation with a symbol for the unknown angle measure.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3437</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>I</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve problems involving measurement and conversion of measurement from a larger unit to a smaller unit.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Know relative sizes of measurement units within one system of units including km, m, cm; kg, g; lb, oz.; l, ml; hr, min, sec. Within a single system of measurement, express measurements in a larger unit in terms of a smaller unit. Record measurement equivalents in a two column table. For example, know that 1 ft is 12 times as long as 1 in. Express the length of a 4 ft snake as 48 in. Generate a conversion table for feet and inches listing the number pairs (1, 12), (2, 24), (3, 36), ...</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3439</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve real-life and mathematical problems using numerical and algebraic expressions and equations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve word problems leading to inequalities of the form px + q &gt; r or px + q &lt; r, where p, q, and r are specific rational numbers. Graph the solution set of the inequality and interpret it in the context of the problem. For example: As a salesperson, you are paid $50 per week plus $3 per sale. This week you want your pay to be at least $100. Write an inequality for the number of sales you need to make, and describe the solutions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3441</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>J</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Geometric measurement: recognize perimeter as an attribute of plane figures and distinguish between linear and area measures.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve real world and mathematical problems involving perimeters of polygons, including finding the perimeter given the side lengths, finding an unknown side length, and exhibiting rectangles with the same perimeter and different areas or with the same area and different perimeters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3443</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve multistep word problems posed with whole numbers and having whole-number answers using the four operations, including problems in which remainders must be interpreted. Represent these problems using equations with a letter standing for the unknown quantity. Assess the reasonableness of answers using mental computation and estimation strategies including rounding.,Multiply a whole number of up to four digits by a one-digit whole number, and multiply two two-digit numbers, using strategies based on place value and the properties of operations. Illustrate and explain the calculation by using equations, rectangular arrays, and/or area models.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3445</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Know and apply the properties of integer exponents to generate equivalent numerical expressions. For example, 3^2 × 3^–5 = 3^–3 = 1/3^3 = 1/27.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3447</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Base arguments on concrete referents such as objects, drawings, diagrams, and actions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use ratio and rate reasoning to solve real-world and mathematical problems, e.g., by reasoning about tables of equivalent ratios, tape diagrams, double number line diagrams, or equations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3449</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Convert like measurement units within a given measurement system.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Convert among different-sized standard measurement units within a given measurement system (e.g., convert 5 cm to 0.05 m), and use these conversions in solving multi-step, real world problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3451</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Identify important quantities in a practical situation and map their relationships (e.g., using diagrams, two-way tables, graphs, flowcharts, or formulas).</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve word problems involving addition and subtraction of fractions referring to the same whole and having like denominators, e.g., by using visual fraction models and equations to represent the problem. </CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3453</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain why the sum or product of two rational numbers is rational; that the sum of a rational number and an irrational number is irrational; and that the product of a nonzero rational number and an irrational number is irrational.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3455</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve linear equations and inequalities in one variable, including equations with coefficients represented by letters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3457</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand ordering and absolute value of rational numbers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3459</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of arithmetic to algebraic expressions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply the properties of operations to generate equivalent expressions. For example, apply the distributive property to the expression 3 (2 + x) to produce the equivalent expression 6 + 3x; apply the distributive property to the expression 24x + 18y to produce the equivalent expression 6 (4x + 3y); apply properties of operations to y + y + y to produce the equivalent expression 3y.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3461</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve word problems leading to inequalities of the form px + q &gt; r or px + q &lt; r, where p, q, and r are specific rational numbers. Graph the solution set of the inequality and interpret it in the context of the problem. For example: As a salesperson, you are paid $50 per week plus $3 per sale. This week you want your pay to be at least $100. Write an inequality for the number of sales you need to make, and describe the solutions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3463</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>I</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Geometric measurement: understand concepts of volume and relate volume to multiplication and to addition.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Relate volume to the operations of multiplication and addition and solve real world and mathematical problems involving volume.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3465</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the four operations with whole numbers to solve problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Multiply or divide to solve word problems involving multiplicative comparison, e.g., by using drawings and equations with a symbol for the unknown number to represent the problem, distinguishing multiplicative comparison from additive comparison.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3467</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the four operations with whole numbers to solve problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Multiply or divide to solve word problems involving multiplicative comparison, e.g., by using drawings and equations with a symbol for the unknown number to represent the problem, distinguishing multiplicative comparison from additive comparison.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3469</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the four operations with whole numbers to solve problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use the four operations with whole numbers to solve problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3471</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve problems involving the four operations, and identify and explain patterns in arithmetic.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve problems involving the four operations, and identify and explain patterns in arithmetic.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3473</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve problems involving the four operations, and identify and explain patterns in arithmetic.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve problems involving the four operations, and identify and explain patterns in arithmetic.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3475</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve real-life and mathematical problems using numerical and algebraic expressions and equations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve word problems leading to inequalities of the form px + q &gt; r or px + q &lt; r, where p, q, and r are specific rational numbers. Graph the solution set of the inequality and interpret it in the context of the problem. For example: As a salesperson, you are paid $50 per week plus $3 per sale. This week you want your pay to be at least $100. Write an inequality for the number of sales you need to make, and describe the solutions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3477</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve real-life and mathematical problems involving angle measure, area, surface area, and volume.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve real-world and mathematical problems involving area, volume and surface area of two- and three-dimensional objects composed of triangles, quadrilaterals, polygons, cubes, and right prisms.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3479</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve real-life and mathematical problems involving angle measure, area, surface area, and volume.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Know the formulas for the area and circumference of a circle and use them to solve problems; give an informal derivation of the relationship between the circumference and area of a circle.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3481</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain equivalence of fractions in special cases, and compare fractions by reasoning about their size.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3483</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand the connections between proportional relationships, lines, and linear equations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Graph proportional relationships, interpreting the unit rate as the slope of the graph. Compare two different proportional relationships represented in different ways. For example, compare a distance-time graph to a distance-time equation to determine which of two moving objects has greater speed.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3485</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>H</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand and apply the Pythagorean Theorem.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply the Pythagorean Theorem to determine unknown side lengths in right triangles in real-world and mathematical problems in two and three dimensions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3487</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze proportional relationships and use them to solve real-world and mathematical problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent proportional relationships by equations. For example, if total cost t is proportional to the number n of items purchased at a constant price p, the relationship between the total cost and the number of items can be expressed as t = pn.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3489</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>I</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve real-world and mathematical problems involving volume of cylinders, cones, and spheres.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Know the formulas for the volumes of cones, cylinders, and spheres and use them to solve real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3491</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use variables to represent quantities in a real-world or mathematical problem, and construct simple equations and inequalities to solve problems by reasoning about the quantities.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3493</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use ratio and rate reasoning to solve real-world and mathematical problems, e.g., by reasoning about tables of equivalent ratios, tape diagrams, double number line diagrams, or equations., Generate two numerical patterns using two given rules. Identify apparent relationships between corresponding terms. Form ordered pairs consisting of corresponding terms from the two patterns, and graph the ordered pairs on a coordinate plane. For example, given the rule “Add 3” and the starting number 0, and given the rule “Add 6” and the starting number 0, generate terms in the resulting sequences, and observe that the terms in one sequence are twice the corresponding terms in the other sequence. Explain informally why this is so.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3495</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of multiplication and division to divide fractions by fractions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Interpret and compute quotients of fractions, and solve word problems involving division of fractions by fractions, e.g., by using visual fraction models and equations to represent the problem. For example, create a story context for (2/3) ÷ (3/4) and use a visual fraction model to show the quotient; use the relationship between multiplication and division to explain that (2/3) ÷ (3/4) = 8/9 because 3/4 of 8/9 is 2/3. (In general, (a/b) ÷ (c/d) = ad/bc.) How much chocolate will each person get if 3 people share 1/2 lb of chocolate equally? How many 3/4-cup servings are in 2/3 of a cup of yogurt? How wide is a rectangular strip of land with length 3/4 mi and area 1/2 square mi?</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3497</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Construct, autonomously, chains of reasoning that will justify or refute propositions or conjectures.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare two fractions with the same numerator or the same denominator by reasoning about their size. Recognize that comparisons are valid only when the two fractions refer to the same whole. Record the results of comparisons with the symbols &gt;, =, or</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3499</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand ratio concepts and use ratio reasoning to solve problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Make tables of equivalent ratios relating quantities with whole number measurements, find missing values in the tables, and plot the pairs of values on the coordinate plane. Use tables to compare ratios.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>TI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3501</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Represent and analyze quantitative relationships between dependent and independent variables.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use variables to represent two quantities in a real-world problem that change in relationship to one another; write an equation to express one quantity, thought of as the dependent variable, in terms of the other quantity, thought of as the independent variable. Analyze the relationship between the dependent and independent variables using graphs and tables, and relate these to the equation. For example, in a problem involving motion at constant speed, list and graph ordered pairs of distances and times, and write the equation d = 65t to represent the relationship between distance and time.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>TI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3503</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>J</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Summarize and describe distributions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Display numerical data in plots on a number line, including dot plots, histograms, and box plots.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3505</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of operations with fractions to add, subtract, multiply, and divide rational numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply properties of operations as strategies to add and subtract rational numbers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3507</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of operations with fractions to add, subtract, multiply, and divide rational numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Convert a rational number to a decimal using long division; know that the decimal form of a rational number terminates in 0s or eventually repeats.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3509</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Work with radicals and integer exponents.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Know and apply the properties of integer exponents to generate equivalent numerical expressions. For example, 3^2 × 3^–5 = 3^–3 = 1/3^3 = 1/27.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3511</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find the volume of a right rectangular prism with fractional edge lengths by packing it with unit cubes of the appropriate unit fraction edge lengths, and show that the volume is the same as would be found by multiplying the edge lengths of the prism. Apply the formulas V = l w h and V = b h to find volumes of right rectangular prisms with fractional edge lengths in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems.,Interpret and compute quotients of fractions, and solve word problems involving division of fractions by fractions, e.g., by using visual fraction models and equations to represent the problem. For example, create a story context for (2/3) ÷ (3/4) and use a visual fraction model to show the quotient; use the relationship between multiplication and division to explain that (2/3) ÷ (3/4) = 8/9 because 3/4 of 8/9 is 2/3. (In general, (a/b) ÷ (c/d) = ad/bc.) How much chocolate will each person get if 3 people share 1/2 lb of chocolate equally? How many 3/4-cup servings are in 2/3 of a cup of yogurt? How wide is a rectangular strip of land with length 3/4 mi and area 1/2 square mi?</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3513</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze proportional relationships and use them to solve real-world and mathematical problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compute unit rates associated with ratios of fractions, including ratios of lengths, areas and other quantities measured in like or different units. For example, if a person walks 1/2 mile in each 1/4 hour, compute the unit rate as the complex fraction 1/2 / 1/4 miles per hour, equivalently 2 miles per hour.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3515</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve real-life and mathematical problems using numerical and algebraic expressions and equations.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve multi-step real-life and mathematical problems posed with positive and negative rational numbers in any form (whole numbers, fractions, and decimals), using tools strategically. Apply properties of operations to calculate with numbers in any form; convert between forms as appropriate; and assess the reasonableness of answers using mental computation and estimation strategies. For example: If a woman making $25 an hour gets a 10% raise, she will make an additional 1/10 of her salary an hour, or $2.50, for a new salary of $27.50. If you want to place a towel bar 9 3/4 inches long in the center of a door that is 27 1/2 inches wide, you will need to place the bar about 9 inches from each edge; this estimate can be used as a check on the exact computation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3517</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use proportional relationships to solve multistep ratio and percent problems. Examples: simple interest, tax, markups and markdowns, gratuities and commissions, fees, percent increase and decrease, percent error.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3519</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve well-posed problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve real-world and mathematical problems involving area, volume and surface area of two- and three-dimensional objects composed of triangles, quadrilaterals, polygons, cubes, and right prisms.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3521</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply the formulas V = l × w × h and V = b × h for rectangular prisms to find volumes of right rectangular prisms with whole number edge lengths in the context of solving real world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3523</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Know and apply the properties of integer exponents to generate equivalent numerical expressions. For example, 3^2 × 3^–5 = 3^–3 = 1/3^3 = 1/27.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3525</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Interpret a multiplication equation as a comparison, e.g., interpret 35 = 5 × 7 as a statement that 35 is 5 times as many as 7 and 7 times as many as 5. Represent verbal statements of multiplicative comparisons as multiplication equations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3527</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Gain familiarity with factors and multiples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find all factor pairs for a whole number in the range 1–100. Recognize that a whole number is a multiple of each of its factors. Determine whether a given whole number in the range 1–100 is a multiple of a given one-digit number. Determine whether a given whole number in the range 1–100 is prime or composite.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3529</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Generalize place value understanding for multi-digit whole numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Read and write multi-digit whole numbers using base-ten numerals, number names, and expanded form. Compare two multi-digit numbers based on meanings of the digits in each place, using &gt;, =, and &lt; symbols to record the results of comparisons.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3531</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Build fractions from unit fractions by applying and extending previous understandings of operations on whole numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of multiplication to multiply a fraction by a whole number.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3533</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Multiply and divide within 100.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Fluently multiply and divide within 100, using strategies such as the relationship between multiplication and division (e.g., knowing that 8 × 5 = 40, one knows 40 ÷ 5 = 8) or properties of operations. By the end of Grade 3, know from memory all products of two one-digit numbers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3535</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>P</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Statistics and Probability: Summarize, represent, and interpret data on a single count or measurement variable.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Summarize, represent, and interpret data on a single count or measurement variable</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3537</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand properties of multiplication and the relationship between multiplication and division.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand division as an unknown-factor problem. For example, find 32 ÷ 8 by finding the number that makes 32 when multiplied by 8.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3539</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Extend understanding of fractions equivalence and ordering.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain why a fraction a/b is equivalent to a fraction (n × a)/(n × b) by using visual fraction models, with attention to how the number and size of the parts differ even though the two fractions themselves are the same size. Use this principle to recognize and generate equivalent fractions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3541</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>I</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Develop understanding of statistical variability.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that a set of data collected to answer a statistical question has a distribution which can be described by its center, spread, and overall shape.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3543</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Draw, construct, and describe geometrical figures and describe the relationship between them.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve problems involving scale drawings of geometric figures, including computing actual lengths and areas from a scale drawing and reproducing a scale drawing at a different scale.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3545</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Construct, autonomously, chains of reasoning that will justify or refute propositions or conjectures.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Fluently multiply multi-digit whole numbers using the standard algorithm.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3547</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Add and subtract mixed numbers with like denominators, e.g., by replacing each mixed number with an equivalent fraction, and/or by using properties of operations and the relationship between addition and subtraction.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3549</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent real world and mathematical problems by graphing points in the first quadrant of the coordinate plane, and interpret coordinate values of points in the context of the situation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3551</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the technique of breaking an argument into cases.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recognize and represent proportional relationships between quantities.,Use ratio and rate reasoning to solve real-world and mathematical problems, e.g., by reasoning about tables of equivalent ratios, tape diagrams, double number line diagrams, or equations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3553</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the technique of breaking an argument into cases.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply properties of operations as strategies to add, subtract, factor, and expand linear expressions with rational coefficients. Give examples of linear equations in one variable with one solution, infinitely many solutions, or no solutions. Show which of these possibilities is the case by successively transforming the given equation into simpler forms, until an equivalent equation of the form x = a, a = a, or a = b results (where a and b are different numbers).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3555</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Identify important quantities in a practical situation and map their relationships (e.g., using diagrams, two-way tables, graphs, flowcharts, or formulas). (DOK 1, 2, 3)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find a percent of a quantity as a rate per 100 (e.g., 30% of a quantity means 30/100 times the quantity); solve problems involving finding the whole, given a part and the percent.,Solve systems of two linear equations in two variables algebraically, and estimate solutions by graphing the equations. Solve simple cases by inspection. For example, 3x + 2y = 5 and 3x + 2y = 6 have no solution because 3x + 2y cannot simultaneously be 5 and 6.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>TI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3557</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find the volume of a right rectangular prism with fractional edge lengths by packing it with unit cubes of the appropriate unit fraction edge lengths, and show that the volume is the same as would be found by multiplying the edge lengths of the prism. Apply the formulas V = l w h and V = b h to find volumes of right rectangular prisms with fractional edge lengths in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems. Apply the formulas V = l × w × h and V = b × h for rectangular prisms to find volumes of right rectangular prisms with whole number edge lengths in the context of solving real world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3559</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Construct, autonomously, chains of reasoning that will justify or refute propositions or conjectures.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that a two-dimensional figure is similar to another if the second can be obtained from the first by a sequence of rotations, reflections, translations, and dilations; given two similar two-dimensional figures, describe a sequence that exhibits the similarity between them.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3561</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Base arguments on concrete referents such as objects, drawings, diagrams, and actions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of addition and subtraction to add and subtract rational numbers; represent addition and subtraction on a horizontal or vertical number line diagram.,Understand ordering and absolute value of rational numbers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3563</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply properties of operations as strategies to add, subtract, factor, and expand linear expressions with rational coefficients.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3565</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Construct, autonomously, chains of reasoning that will justify or refute propositions or conjectures.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write and evaluate numerical expressions involving whole-number exponents.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3567</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>O</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Geometry: Define trigonometric ratios and solve problems involving right triangles.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that by similarity, side ratios in right triangles are properties of the angles in the triangle, leading to definitions of trigonometric ratios for acute angles.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3569</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>J</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Investigate patterns of association in bivariate data.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use the equation of a linear model to solve problems in the context of bivariate measurement data, interpreting the slope and intercept. For example, in a linear model for a biology experiment, interpret a slope of 1.5 cm/hr as meaning that an additional hour of sunlight each day is associated with an additional 1.5 cm in mature plant height.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3571</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of multiplication to multiply a fraction by a whole number.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3573</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Reason about and solve one-variable equations and inequalities.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand solving an equation or inequality as a process of answering a question: which values from a specified set, if any, make the equation or inequality true? Use substitution to determine whether a given number in a specified set makes an equation or inequality true.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3575</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>State logical assumptions being used.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recognize and represent proportional relationships between quantities.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3577</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use informal arguments to establish facts about the angle sum and exterior angle of triangles, about the angles created when parallel lines are cut by a transversal, and the angle-angle criterion for similarity of triangles. For example, arrange three copies of the same triangle so that the sum of the three angles appears to form a line, and give an argument in terms of transversals why this is so.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3579</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>B</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand properties of multiplication and the relationship between multiplication and division.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply properties of operations as strategies to multiply and divide.2 Examples: If 6 × 4 = 24 is known, then 4 × 6 = 24 is also known. (Commutative property of multiplication.) 3 × 5 × 2 can be found by 3 × 5 = 15, then 15 × 2 = 30, or by 5 × 2 = 10, then 3 × 10 = 30. (Associative property of multiplication.) Knowing that 8 × 5 = 40 and 8 × 2 = 16, one can find 8 × 7 as 8 × (5 + 2) = (8 × 5) + (8 × 2) = 40 + 16 = 56. (Distributive property.)</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3581</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>I</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Investigate chance processes and develop, use, and evaluate probability models.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that the probability of a chance event is a number between 0 and 1 that expresses the likelihood of the event occurring. Larger numbers indicate greater likelihood. A probability near 0 indicates an unlikely event, a probability around 1/2 indicates an event that is neither unlikely nor likely, and a probability near 1 indicates a likely event.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3583</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Test propositions or conjectures with specific examples.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recognize and represent proportional relationships between quantities.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3585</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Reason about and solve one-variable equations and inequalities.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand solving an equation or inequality as a process of answering a question: which values from a specified set, if any, make the equation or inequality true? Use substitution to determine whether a given number in a specified set makes an equation or inequality true.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3587</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use functions to model relationships between quantities.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Construct a function to model a linear relationship between two quantities. Determine the rate of change and initial value of the function from a description of a relationship or from two (x, y) values, including reading these from a table or from a graph. Interpret the rate of change and initial value of a linear function in terms of the situation it models, and in terms of its graph or a table of values.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3589</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use properties of operations to generate equivalent expressions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply properties of operations as strategies to add, subtract, factor, and expand linear expressions with rational coefficients.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3591</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Find the volume of a right rectangular prism with fractional edge lengths by packing it with unit cubes of the appropriate unit fraction edge lengths, and show that the volume is the same as would be found by multiplying the edge lengths of the prism. Apply the formulas V = l w h and V = b h to find volumes of right rectangular prisms with fractional edge lengths in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems. Solve real-world and mathematical problems involving area, volume and surface area of two- and three-dimensional objects composed of triangles, quadrilaterals, polygons, cubes, and right prisms.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3593</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the technique of breaking an argument into cases.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare two fractions with different numerators and different denominators, e.g., by creating common denominators or numerators, or by comparing to a benchmark fraction such as 1/2. Recognize that comparisons are valid only when the two fractions refer to the same whole. Record the results of comparisons with symbols &gt;, =, or &lt;, and justify the conclusions, e.g., by using a visual fraction model.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>GI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3595</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply mathematics to solve problems arising in everyday life, society, and the workplace.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve unit rate problems including those involving unit pricing and constant speed. For example, if it took 7 hours to mow 4 lawns, then at that rate, how many lawns could be mowed in 35 hours? At what rate were lawns being mowed?</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3597</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply properties of operations as strategies to multiply and divide.2 Examples: If 6 × 4 = 24 is known, then 4 × 6 = 24 is also known. (Commutative property of multiplication.) 3 × 5 × 2 can be found by 3 × 5 = 15, then 15 × 2 = 30, or by 5 × 2 = 10, then 3 × 10 = 30. (Associative property of multiplication.) Knowing that 8 × 5 = 40 and 8 × 2 = 16, one can find 8 × 7 as 8 × (5 + 2) = (8 × 5) + (8 × 2) = 40 + 16 = 56. (Distributive property.)</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3599</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>I</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Algebra: Solve equations and inequalities in one variable.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Solve linear equations and inequalities in one variable, including equations with coefficients represented by letters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3601</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>State logical assumptions being used.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use place value understanding and properties of operations to perform multi-digit arithmetic.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3603</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use functions to model relationships between quantities.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Describe qualitatively the functional relationship between two quantities by analyzing a graph (e.g., where the function is increasing or decreasing, linear or nonlinear). Sketch a graph that exhibits the qualitative features of a function that has been described verbally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3605</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>K</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Classify two-dimensional figures into categories based on their properties.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that attributes belonging to a category of two-dimensional figures also belong to all subcategories of that category. For example, all rectangles have four right angles and squares are rectangles, so all squares have four right angles.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3607</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Distinguish correct logic or reasoning from that which is flawed, and—if there is a flaw in the argument—explain what it is.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Multiply a whole number of up to four digits by a one-digit whole number, and multiply two two-digit numbers, using strategies based on place value and the properties of operations. Illustrate and explain the calculation by using equations, rectangular arrays, and/or area models.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3609</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use properties of operations to generate equivalent expressions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply properties of operations as strategies to add, subtract, factor, and expand linear expressions with rational coefficients.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3611</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze proportional relationships and use them to solve real-world and mathematical problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain what a point (x, y) on the graph of a proportional relationship means in terms of the situation, with special attention to the points (0, 0) and (1, r) where r is the unit rate.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3613</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Base arguments on concrete referents such as objects, drawings, diagrams, and actions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Classify two-dimensional figures into categories based on their properties.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3615</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply the properties of operations to generate equivalent expressions. For example, apply the distributive property to the expression 3 (2 + x) to produce the equivalent expression 6 + 3x; apply the distributive property to the expression 24x + 18y to produce the equivalent expression 6 (4x + 3y); apply properties of operations to y + y + y to produce the equivalent expression 3y.,Find the area of right triangles, other triangles, special quadrilaterals, and polygons by composing into rectangles or decomposing into triangles and other shapes; apply these techniques in the context of solving real-world and mathematical problems.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3617</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Base arguments on concrete referents such as objects, drawings, diagrams, and actions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Tell and write time to the nearest minute and measure time intervals in minutes. Solve word problems involving addition and subtraction of time intervals in minutes, e.g., by representing the problem on a number line diagram.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3619</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Build fractions from unit fractions by applying and extending previous understandings of operations on whole numbers.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand a fraction a/b with a &gt; 1 as a sum of fractions 1/b.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3621</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze proportional relationships and use them to solve real-world and mathematical problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recognize and represent proportional relationships between quantities.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3623</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Apply and extend previous understandings of arithmetic to algebraic expressions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply the properties of operations to generate equivalent expressions. For example, apply the distributive property to the expression 3 (2 + x) to produce the equivalent expression 6 + 3x; apply the distributive property to the expression 24x + 18y to produce the equivalent expression 6 (4x + 3y); apply properties of operations to y + y + y to produce the equivalent expression 3y.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3625</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Represent and solve problems involving multiplication and division., Work with equal groups of objects to gain foundations for multiplication.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3627</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use properties of operations to generate equivalent expressions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Apply properties of operations as strategies to add, subtract, factor, and expand linear expressions with rational coefficients.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3629</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>D</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use the technique of breaking an argument into cases.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand ordering and absolute value of rational numbers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3631</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH2</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Interpret results in the context of a situation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Fluently add and subtract within 1000 using strategies and algorithms based on place value, properties of operations, and/or the relationship between addition and subtraction.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3633</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH4</Claim>
		<Target>E</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Analyze the adequacy of and make improvements to an existing model or develop a mathematical model of a real phenomenon.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use functions to model relationships between quantities.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3635</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>C</Target>
		<TargetDesc>State logical assumptions being used.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use proportional relationships to solve multistep ratio and percent problems. Examples: simple interest, tax, markups and markdowns, gratuities and commissions, fees, percent increase and decrease, percent error. Use ratio and rate reasoning to solve real-world and mathematical problems, e.g., by reasoning about tables of equivalent ratios, tape diagrams, double number line diagrams, or equations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3637</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>F</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Base arguments on concrete referents such as objects, drawings, diagrams, and actions.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain why a fraction a/b is equivalent to a fraction (n × a)/(n × b) by using visual fraction models, with attention to how the number and size of the parts differ even though the two fractions themselves are the same size. Use this principle to recognize and generate equivalent fractions. Compare two fractions with different numerators and different denominators, e.g., by creating common denominators or numerators, or by comparing to a benchmark fraction such as 1/2. Recognize that comparisons are valid only when the two fractions refer to the same whole. Record the results of comparisons with symbols &gt;, =, or &lt;, and justify the conclusions, e.g., by using a visual fraction model.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3639</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH3</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>At later grades, determine conditions under which an argument does and does not apply. (For example, area increases with perimeter for squares, but not for all plane figures.)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Interpret the equation y = mx + b as defining a linear function, whose graph is a straight line; give examples of functions that are not linear. For example, the function A = s^2 giving the area of a square as a function of its side length is not linear because its graph contains the points (1,1), (2,4) and (3,9), which are not on a straight line.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3641</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Use random sampling to draw inferences about a population.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand that statistics can be used to gain information about a population by examining a sample of the population; generalizations about a population from a sample are valid only if the sample is representative of that population. Understand that random sampling tends to produce representative samples and support valid inferences.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3643</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>G</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Solve problems involving measurement and estimation of intervals of time, liquid volumes, and masses of objects.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Tell and write time to the nearest minute and measure time intervals in minutes. Solve word problems involving addition and subtraction of time intervals in minutes, e.g., by representing the problem on a number line diagram.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3674</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>MATH1</Claim>
		<Target>A</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Understand ratio concepts and use ratio reasoning to solve problems.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Understand the concept of a ratio and use ratio language to describe a ratio relationship between two quantities. For example, “The ratio of wings to beaks in the bird house at the zoo was 2:1, because for every 2 wings there was 1 beak.” “For every vote candidate A received, candidate C received nearly three votes.”</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2903</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES &amp; FEATURES: Relate knowledge of structural elements of texts or text features to obtain, interpret, explain, or connect information within texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Refer to details and examples in a text when explaining what the text says explicitly and when drawing inferences from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2918</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive/opinion texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2970</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>10</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended or precise meanings of words, including domainspecific (tier 3) words and words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word relationships (e.g., antonyms, homographs), word structure (e.g., common Greek or Latin roots, affixes), or use of resources (e.g., dictionary, glossary, inset text)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including figurative, connotative, and technical meanings; analyze the impact of a specific word choice on meaning and tone.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3056</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EVALUATE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Evaluate relevancy, accuracy, and completeness of information from multiple sources</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple authoritative print and digital sources, using advanced searches effectively; assess the strengths and limitations of each source in terms of the specific task, purpose, and audience; integrate information into the text selectively to maintain the flow of ideas, avoiding plagiarism and overreliance on any one source and following a standard format for citation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3040</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>11</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Use supporting evidence to justify interpretations of information presented or how it is integrated (author’s reasoning; interactions among events, concepts, people, or development of ideas)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite several pieces of textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3141</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply narrative strategies (e.g., dialogue, description) and appropriate text structures and transitions when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of narrative text (e.g., introduce narrator or use dialogue when describing an event)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective technique, relevant descriptive details, and well-structured event sequences.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2876</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>INTERPRET &amp; INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Locate information to support central ideas and subtopics; Select and integrate information from data or print and non-print text sources</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall information from experiences or gather information from print and digital sources; take brief notes on sources and sort evidence into provided categories.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3143</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>12</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYSIS WITHIN OR ACROSS TEXTS: Analyze texts to determine how connections are made in development of complex ideas or events; or in development of topics, themes, rhetorical features</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine an author’s point of view or purpose in a text in which the rhetoric is particularly effective, analyzing how style and content contribute to the power, persuasiveness, or beauty of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2814</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Identify the reasons and evidence a speaker provides to support particular points.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3091</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Cite explicit textual evidence to support inferences made or conclusions drawn about texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite strong and thorough textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text, including determining where the text leaves matters uncertain.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3012</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas/ key events</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a theme or central idea of a text and how it is conveyed through particular details; provide a summary of the text distinct from personal opinions or judgments.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2833</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive/opinion texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing. B) Use commas and quotation marks to mark direct speech and quotations from a text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3679</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support analyses, arguments, or critiques</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple print and digital sources; assess the credibility of each source; and quote or paraphrase the data and conclusions of others while avoiding plagiarism and providing basic bibliographic information for sources.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	    <Section>3</Section>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2889</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES &amp; FEATURES: Relate knowledge of text structures or text features (e.g., illustrations) to gain, interpret, explain, or connect information</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Refer to parts of stories, dramas, and poems when writing or speaking about a text, using terms such as chapter, scene, and stanza; describe how each successive part builds on earlier sections.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2905</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended meanings of words, including words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word relationships (e.g., synonyms), word structure (e.g., common Greek or Latin roots, affixes), or use of resources (e.g., dictionary, thesaurus)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including those that allude to significant characters found in mythology (e.g., Herculean).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2703</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>7</Target>
		<TargetDesc>COMPOSE FULL TEXTS: Write full arguments about topics using a complete writing process attending to purpose and audience: establish and support a claim; organize, elaborate, and cite supporting evidence from credible sources; provide appropriate transitional strategies for coherence; and develop a conclusion that is appropriate to purpose and audience and follows from and supports the argument(s) presented.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write arguments to support claims in an analysis of substantive topics or texts, using valid reasoning and relevant and sufficient evidence. Develop claim(s) and counterclaims fairly and thoroughly, supplying the most relevant evidence for each while pointing out the strengths and limitations of both in a manner that anticipates the audience’s knowledge level, concerns, values, and possible biases.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>WER</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2865</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Generate conjectures or opinions and cite evidence to support them based on prior knowledge and evidence collected and analyzed</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall information from experiences or gather information from print and digital sources; take brief notes on sources and sort evidence into provided categories.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2998</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas, key events, procedures, or topics and subtopics</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a central idea of a text and how it is conveyed through particular details; provide a summary of the text distinct from personal opinions or judgments.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2961</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing. A) Use a comma to separate coordinate adjectives (e.g., It was a fascinating, enjoyable movie but not He wore an old[,] green shirt).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3685</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Summarize the points a speaker makes and explain how each claim is supported by reasons and evidence.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2878</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Use supporting evidence to justify interpretations (theme, events, conflicts/challenges, setting, character development/ interactions, point of view)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare and contrast two or more characters, settings, or events in a story or drama, drawing on specific details in the text (e.g., how characters interact).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2869</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES &amp; FEATURES: Relate knowledge of text structures or text features (e.g., visual or graphic elements) to analyze interpret, or connect information within a text</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain how a series of chapters, scenes, or stanzas fits together to provide the overall structure of a particular story, drama, or poem.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2886</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Use supporting evidence to interpret and explain inferences about character traits, motivations, feelings; point of view, author’s lesson or message</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Describe characters in a story (e.g., their traits, motivations, or feelings) and explain how their actions contribute to the sequence of events.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2973</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Delineate a speaker’s argument and specific claims, evaluating the soundness of the reasoning and the relevance and sufficiency of the evidence.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3107</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas, topics/subtopics, key events, or procedures using supporting ideas and relevant details</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine two or more central ideas of a text and analyze their development over the course of the text, including how they interact and build on one another to provide a complex analysis; provide an objective summary of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3155</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>13</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES &amp; FEATURES: Relate knowledge of text structures (e.g., organization of a paragraph) or text features to analyze the impact (advantages/disadvantages) of those choices on meaning or presentation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare and contrast the structure of two or more texts and analyze how the differing structure of each text contributes to its meaning and style.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3095</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Cite explicit textual evidence to support inferences made or conclusions drawn about texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite strong and thorough textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text, including determining where the text leaves matters uncertain.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2981</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the main ideas and supporting details presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and explain how the ideas clarify a topic, text, or issue under study.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2839</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas, key events, procedures, or topics and subtopics</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine two or more main ideas of a text and explain how they are supported by key details; summarize the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2992</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EVALUATE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Use reasoning, planning, and evidence to gather and select information to support inferences, interpretations, and analyses</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple print and digital sources; assess the credibility of each source; and quote or paraphrase the data and conclusions of others while avoiding plagiarism and providing basic bibliographic information for sources.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3000</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE &amp; VOCABULARY USE: Strategically use precise language and vocabulary (including academic words and domain-specific vocabulary figurative language,) and style appropriate to the purpose and audience when revising or composing texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas, concepts, and information through the selection, organization, and analysis of relevant content. D) Use precise language and domain-specific vocabulary to inform about or explain the topic.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3014</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>5</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYSIS WITHIN OR ACROSS TEXTS: Analyze how information is presented within or across texts showing relationships among the targeted aspects (the influence of differing points of view, various formats/media, use of source material)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Describe how a particular story’s or drama’s plot unfolds in a series of episodes as well as how the characters respond or change as the plot moves toward a resolution.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3157</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas, topics/subtopics, key events, or procedures using supporting ideas and details</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a theme or central idea of a text and analyze its development over the course of the text, including its relationship to the characters, setting, and plot; provide an objective summary of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3043</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English grammar and usage when writing or speaking.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2820</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE &amp; VOCABULARY USE: Strategically use language and vocabulary (including academic or domain-specific vocabulary) appropriate to the purpose and audience when revising or composing texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use knowledge of language and its conventions when writing, speaking, reading, or listening. A) Choose words and phrases for effect.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3088</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the purpose of information presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and evaluate the motives (e.g., social, commercial, political) behind its presentation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3175</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES &amp; FEATURES: Analyze text structures and the impact of those choices on meaning or presentation.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite several pieces of textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2701</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYZE/INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Gather, analyze, and integrate multiple sources of information/evidence to support a presentation on a topic.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple authoritative print and digital sources, using advanced searches effectively; assess the strengths and limitations of each source in terms of the task, purpose, and audience; integrate information into the text selectively to maintain the flow of ideas, avoiding plagiarism and overreliance on any one source and following a standard format for citation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3169</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Identify explicit textual evidence to support inferences made or conclusions drawn</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite several pieces of textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2636</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support arguments, ideas, or analyses.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2829</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Identify the reasons and evidence a speaker provides to support particular points.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3067</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply a variety of strategies when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of informational texts: organizing ideas by stating a thesis and maintaining a focus, developing a complex topic/subtopics, including relevant supporting evidence (from texts when appropriate) and elaboration, or providing a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine and convey complex ideas, concepts, and information clearly and accurately through the effective selection, organization, and analysis of content. F) Provide a concluding statement or section that follows from and supports the information or explanation presented (e.g., articulating implications or the significance of the topic).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2696</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EVALUATE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Use reasoning, evaluation, and evidence to assess the credibility and accuracy of each source in order to gather and select information to support analysis, reflection, and research.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple print and digital sources, using search terms effectively; assess the credibility and accuracy of each source; and quote or paraphrase the data and conclusions of others while avoiding plagiarism and following a standard format for citation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2897</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Identify or summarize central ideas/ key events</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a theme of a story, drama, or poem from details in the text; summarize the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3115</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>7</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Determine or interpret impact or intent of figurative language/literary devices or connotative meanings of words and phrases used in context and the impact of those word choices on meaning and tone</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including figurative and connotative meanings; analyze the impact of specific word choices on meaning and tone, including analogies or allusions to other texts.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2860</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the main ideas and supporting details of a text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2958</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Write or revise one or more paragraphs demonstrating ability to organize ideas by stating a focus, including supporting evidence and elaboration, or writing body paragraphs or a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas and information clearly. Develop the topic with facts, definitions, concrete details, quotations, or other information and examples related to the topic.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2871</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Use supporting evidence to justify interpretations (theme, events, conflicts/challenges, setting, character development/ interactions, point of view)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare and contrast two or more characters, settings, or events in a story or drama, drawing on specific details in the text (e.g., how characters interact).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2967</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Use explicit details and implicit information from texts to support inferences or analyses of the information presented</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite several pieces of textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3010</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas/ key events</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a theme or central idea of a text and how it is conveyed through particular details; provide a summary of the text distinct from personal opinions or judgments.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3109</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>11</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVALUATION: Apply reasoning and a range of textual evidence to or justify analyses of author’s presentation of information (author’s line of reasoning, point of view/purpose; relevance of evidence or elaboration to support claims; development or connections among complex concepts ideas)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine an author’s point of view or purpose in a text in which the rhetoric is particularly effective, analyzing how style and content contribute to the power, persuasiveness, or beauty of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2898</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended meanings of words, including words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word relationships (e.g., synonyms), word structure (e.g., common Greek or Latin roots, affixes), or use of resources (e.g., dictionary, thesaurus)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including those that allude to significant characters found in mythology (e.g., Herculean).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2901</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES &amp; FEATURES: Relate knowledge of structural elements of texts or text features to obtain, interpret, explain, or connect information within texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Refer to details and examples in a text when explaining what the text says explicitly and when drawing inferences from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3004</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>11</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Use supporting evidence to justify interpretations or analyses of information presented or how information is integrated within a text (point of view; interactions among events, concepts, people, or ideas; author’s reasoning and evidence)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine an author’s point of view or purpose in a text and explain how it is conveyed in the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2988</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas, key events, procedures, or topics and subtopics</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a central idea of a text and how it is conveyed through particular details; provide a summary of the text distinct from personal opinions or judgments.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2971</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>13</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES &amp; FEATURES: Relate knowledge of text structures and genre-specific features to compare or analyze the impact of those choices on meaning or presentation</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the structure an author uses to organize a text, including how the major sections contribute to the whole and to the development of the ideas.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2884</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended meanings of words, including words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word relationships, word structure (e.g., common roots, affixes), or use of resources (e.g., beginning dictionary)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, distinguishing literal from non-literal language.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2872</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>INTERPRET &amp; INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Locate information to support central ideas and subtopics; Select and integrate information from data or print and non-print text sources</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall relevant information from experiences or gather relevant information from print and digital sources; take notes and categorize information, and provide a list of sources.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3119</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVALUATION: Apply reasoning and a range of textual evidence to justify inferences or judgments made (development of characters/setting/plot, point of view, theme, use of dialogue)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze how a text makes connections among and distinctions between individuals, ideas, or events (e.g., through comparisons, analogies, or categories).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3070</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Delineate a speaker’s argument and specific claims, evaluating the soundness of the reasoning and relevance and sufficiency of the evidence and identifying when irrelevant evidence is introduced.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3181</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>14</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Interpret impact or intent of figurative language/literary devices or connotative meanings of words and phrases used in context</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate understanding of figurative language, word relationships, and nuances in word meanings.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2966</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing. B) Spell correctly.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2664</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>INTERPRET/INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Locate information to support central ideas and subtopics that are provided; select and integrate information from data or print and non-print text sources for a given purpose.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3137</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Identify explicit textual evidence to support inferences made or conclusions drawn</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite the textual evidence that most strongly supports an analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2977</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Interpret information presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and explain how it contributes to a topic, text, or issue under study.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2942</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive/opinion texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3047</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EVALUATE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Distinguish relevant-irrelevant information (e.g., fact/opinion)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2974</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the main ideas and supporting details presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and explain how the ideas clarify a topic, text, or issue under study.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2810</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Identify the reasons and evidence a speaker provides to support particular points.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2830</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Paraphrase portions of a text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2891</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>7</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Interpret use of language by distinguishing literal from non-literal meanings of words and phrases used in context</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, distinguishing literal from non-literal language.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2702</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support arguments, ideas, analyses, hypotheses, or conjectures.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2648</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYZE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Distinguish relevant/irrelevant information.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3147</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply a variety of strategies when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of text that express arguments about topics or texts: establishing a precise claim, organizing and citing supporting evidence (from texts when appropriate) and counter claims using credible sources, or providing a conclusion (e.g., articulating implications or stating significance of the problem) appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write arguments to support claims in an analysis of substantive topics or texts, using valid reasoning and relevant and sufficient evidence. Use words, phrases, and clauses as well as varied syntax to link the major sections of the text, create cohesion, and clarify the relationships between claim(s) and reasons, between reasons and evidence, and between claim(s) and counterclaims.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3180</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>14</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Interpret use of language by distinguishing literal from non-literal meanings of words and phrases used in context</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Distinguish the literal and non-literal meanings of words and phrases in context (e.g., take steps).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3058</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive/argument texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing. A) Observe hyphenation conventions.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3104</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>14</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Analyze the figurative (e.g., euphemism, oxymoron, hyperbole, paradox) or connotative meanings of words and phrases used in context and the impact of these word choices on meaning and tone</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate understanding of figurative language, word relationships, and nuances in word meanings. A) Interpret figures of speech (e.g., hyperbole, paradox) in context and analyze their role in the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2831</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the main ideas and supporting details of a text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2888</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Use supporting evidence to interpret and explain inferences about character traits, motivations, feelings; point of view, author’s lesson or message</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Describe characters in a story (e.g., their traits, motivations, or feelings) and explain how their actions contribute to the sequence of events.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2924</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>5</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYSIS WITHIN OR ACROSS TEXTS: Specify or compare relationships across texts (e.g., literary elements, problem solution, theme)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Describe characters in a story (e.g., their traits, motivations, or feelings) and explain how their actions contribute to the sequence of events.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2940</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Write or revise one or more paragraphs demonstrating specific narrative strategies (use of dialogue, sensory or concrete details, description), chronology, or authors’ craft appropriate to purpose (detailing characters, plot, setting, or an event)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective technique, descriptive details, and clear event sequences. Use narrative techniques, such as dialogue, description, and pacing, to develop experiences and events or show the responses of characters to situations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2867</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>7</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Identify or interpret figurative language (e.g., metaphors, similes, idioms), literary devices, or connotative meanings of words and phrases used in context</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate understanding of figurative language, word relationships, and nuances in word meanings.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2983</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the main ideas and supporting details presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and explain how the ideas clarify a topic, text, or issue under study.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3062</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE &amp; VOCABULARY USE: Strategically use precise language and vocabulary (including academic and domain-specific vocabulary and figurative language) and style appropriate to the purpose and audience when revising or composing texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine and convey complex ideas, concepts, and information clearly and accurately through the effective selection, organization, and analysis of content. D) Use precise language, domain-specific vocabulary, and techniques such as metaphor, simile, and analogy to manage the complexity of the topic.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3103</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>13</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES/ FEATURES: Relate knowledge of text structures or formats, or genre features (e.g., graphic/visual information) to integrate information or analyze the impact on meaning or presentation</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze and evaluate the effectiveness of the structure an author uses in his or her exposition or argument, including whether the structure makes points clear, convincing, and engaging.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2926</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EVALUATE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Distinguish relevant-irrelevant information (e.g., fact/opinion)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall information from experiences or gather information from print and digital sources; take brief notes on sources and sort evidence into provided categories.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3131</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Evaluate a speaker’s point of view, reasoning, and use of evidence and rhetoric, assessing the stance, premises, links among ideas, word choice, points of emphasis, and tone used.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3097</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas/key events using key relevant details)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine two or more themes or central ideas of a text and analyze their development over the course of the text, including how they interact and build on one another to produce a complex account; provide an objective summary of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3022</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended, precise, or nuanced meanings of words, including words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word patterns, parts of speech, or use of resources (e.g., dictionary, thesaurus, digital tools)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including figurative and connotative meanings; analyze the impact of a specific word choice on meaning and tone.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2666</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support opinions, ideas, or analyses.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall relevant information from experiences or gather relevant information from print and digital sources; take notes and categorize information, and provide a list of sources.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2986</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>INTERPRET &amp; INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Locate information to support central ideas and subtopics; Select and integrate information from data or print and non-print text sources</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall relevant information from experiences or gather relevant information from print and digital sources; summarize or paraphrase information in notes and finished work, and provide a list of sources.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3020</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES &amp; FEATURES: Relate knowledge of text structures or text features (e.g., layout; visual or auditory elements – lighting, camera effects, music; symbolic or graphic representations) to analyze impact on meaning, style, or presentation</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze how a particular sentence, chapter, scene, or stanza fits into the overall structure of a text and contributes to the development of the theme, setting, or plot.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3135</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Evaluate a speaker’s point of view, reasoning, and use of evidence and rhetoric, assessing the stance, premises, links among ideas, word choice, points of emphasis, and tone used.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2913</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Write or revise one or more paragraphs demonstrating ability to organize ideas by stating a focus, including supporting evidence and elaboration, or writing body paragraphs or a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas and information clearly. Link ideas within categories of information using words and phrases (e.g., another, for example, also, because).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2646</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support opinions, ideas, or analyses.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall relevant information from experiences or gather relevant information from print and digital sources; summarize or paraphrase information in notes and finished work, and provide a list of sources</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3059</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive/argument texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing. B) Spell correctly.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3093</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Cite explicit textual evidence to support inferences made or conclusions drawn about texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite strong and thorough textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text, including determining where the text leaves matters uncertain.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3183</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>11</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVALUATION: Apply reasoning and a range of textual evidence to justify inferences or interpret author’s presentation of information (author’s line of reasoning, point of view/purpose support claims, concepts, ideas; relevance of evidence or elaboration to support claims)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite the textual evidence that most strongly supports an analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3178</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>12</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYSIS WITHIN OR ACROSS TEXTS: Specify, integrate, or compare information within or across texts (e.g., cause effect, integrate information)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Ask and answer questions to demonstrate understanding of a text, referring explicitly to the text as the basis for the answers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3160</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>14</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Interpret use of language by distinguishing literal from non-literal meanings of words and phrases used in context</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate understanding of word relationships and nuances in word meanings. A) Distinguish the literal and non-literal meanings of words and phrases in context (e.g., take steps).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3080</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Evaluate a speaker’s point of view, reasoning, and use of evidence and rhetoric, assessing the stance, premises, links among ideas, word choice, points of emphasis, and tone used.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2994</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Generate conjectures or opinions and cite evidence to support them based on prior knowledge and evidence collected and analyzed</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research. A) Apply grade 5 Reading standards to literature (e.g., “Compare and contrast two or more characters, settings, or events in a story or a drama, drawing on specific details in the text [e.g., how characters interact]”).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3110</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas/key events using key details from the text</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a central idea of a text and analyze its development over the course of the text, including its relationship to supporting ideas; provide an objective summary of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2984</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Delineate a speaker’s argument and specific claims, distinguishing claims that are supported by reasons and evidence from claims that are not.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2969</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas, key events, procedures, or topics and subtopics</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine two or more central ideas in a text and analyze their development over the course of the text; provide an objective summary of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3054</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EVALUATE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Use reasoning, planning, and evidence to gather and select information to support inferences, interpretations, and analyses</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple print and digital sources, using search terms effectively; assess the credibility and accuracy of each source; and quote or paraphrase the data and conclusions of others while avoiding plagiarism and following a standard format for citation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3074</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply a variety of strategies when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of text that express arguments about topics or texts: establishing and supporting a claim, organizing and citing supporting evidence using credible sources, appropriate vocabulary, or providing a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write arguments to support claims with clear reasons and relevant evidence. Support claim(s) with logical reasoning and relevant evidence, using accurate, credible sources and demonstrating an understanding of the topic or text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3108</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>10</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended or precise meanings of words, including domain-specific/technical (tier 3) terms, distinguishing connotation-denotation, and words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word patterns, relationships, etymology, or use of specialized resources (e.g., dictionary, glossary, digital tools)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including figurative, connotative, and technical meanings; analyze how an author uses and refines the meaning of a key term or terms over the course of a text (e.g., how Madison defines faction in Federalist No. 10).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2852</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Identify or summarize central ideas, key events, or procedures</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the main idea of a text and explain how it is supported by key details; summarize the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2856</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>10</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended meanings of words, including domain-specific (tier 3) words and academic (tier 2) words with multiple meanings, based on context, word relationships (e.g., synonyms), word structure (e.g., common Greek or Latin roots, affixes), or use of resources (e.g., dictionary, glossary)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of general academic and domain-specific words or phrases in a text relevant to a grade 4 topic or subject area.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2700</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EVALUATE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Use reasoning, evaluation, and evidence to assess the credibility and accuracy of each source in order to gather and select information to support analysis, reflection, and research. Evaluate relevance, accuracy, and completeness of information from multiple sources.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple authoritative print and digital sources, using advanced searches effectively; assess the strengths and limitations of each source in terms of the task, purpose, and audience; integrate information into the text selectively to maintain the flow of ideas, avoiding plagiarism and overreliance on any one source and following a standard format for citation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3111</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas/key events using key details from the text</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a central idea of a text and analyze its development over the course of the text, including its relationship to supporting ideas; provide an objective summary of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3117</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Apply reasoning and a range of textual evidence to justify inferences or judgments made (development of characters/setting/plot, point of view, theme, use of dialogue)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze how a text makes connections among and distinctions between individuals, ideas, or events (e.g., through comparisons, analogies, or categories).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2968</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas, key events, procedures, or topics and subtopics</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine two or more central ideas in a text and analyze their development over the course of the text; provide an objective summary of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3084</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing. C) Spell correctly.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2822</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive/opinion texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing. C) Use commas and quotation marks in dialogue.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3045</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply a variety of strategies when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of informational text: organizing ideas by stating and maintaining a focus/tone, developing a topic including relevant supporting evidence/ vocabulary and elaboration, or providing a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas, concepts, and information through the selection, organization, and analysis of relevant content.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3101</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas/key events using key relevant details)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine two or more themes or central ideas of a text and analyze their development over the course of the text, including how they interact and build on one another to produce a complex account; provide an objective summary of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3186</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas/key events using key details from the text</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a theme or central idea of a text and analyze its development over the course of the text; provide an objective summary of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3676</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support analyses, arguments, or critiques</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Support claim(s) with clear reasons and relevant evidence, using credible sources and demonstrating an understanding of the topic or text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
		<Section>2</Section>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3197</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support analyses, arguments, or critiques</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research. </CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2558</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>COMPOSE FULL TEXTS: Write full informational texts on a topic using a complete writing process attending to purpose and audience: organize ideas by stating a focus (main idea); include text structures and appropriate transitional strategies for coherence; include elaboration and supporting evidence from sources and an appropriate conclusion.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas and information clearly. Develop the topic with facts, definitions, and details. </CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>WER</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2963</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply narrative strategies (e.g., dialogue, description) and appropriate text structures and transitions when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of narrative text (e.g., introduce narrator or use dialogue when describing an event)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective technique, relevant descriptive details, and well-structured event sequences. Engage and orient the reader by establishing a context and introducing a narrator and/or characters; organize an event sequence that unfolds naturally and logically.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2863</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the main ideas and supporting details of a text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2843</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>12</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYSIS WITHIN OR ACROSS TEXTS: Analyze or compare how information is presented within or across texts showing relationships among targeted aspects (point of view, genre features, topic)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain the relationships or interactions between two or more individuals, events, ideas, or concepts in a historical, scientific, or technical text based on specific information in the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2944</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support analyses, arguments, or critiques</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3068</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Delineate a speaker’s argument and specific claims, evaluating the soundness of the reasoning and relevance and sufficiency of the evidence and identifying when irrelevant evidence is introduced.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3167</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>5</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYSIS WITHIN OR ACROSS TEXTS: Analyze how information is presented showing relationships among literary elements within or across texts (dialogue, advancing action, character actions/interactions) or use of source material to develop literary elements</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze how an author develops and contrasts the points of view of different characters or narrators in a text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2649</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>7</Target>
		<TargetDesc>COMPOSE FULL TEXTS: Write full opinion pieces about topics using a complete writing process attending to purpose and audience: organize ideas by stating a context and focus (opinion); include structures and appropriate transitional strategies for coherence; elaborate and include supporting evidence/reasons from sources; and develop an appropriate conclusion related to the opinion presented.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write opinion pieces on topics or texts, supporting a point of view with reasons and information. Provide logically ordered reasons that are supported by facts and details.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>WER</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2827</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive/opinion texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3133</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Evaluate a speaker’s point of view, reasoning, and use of evidence and rhetoric, assessing the stance, premises, links among ideas, word choice, points of emphasis, and tone used.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3158</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Identify explicit text evidence to support inferences made or conclusions drawn about texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite the textual evidence that most strongly supports an analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3013</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Apply reasoning and a range of textual evidence (e.g., quotes, examples, details) to justify analyses or judgments made about intended effects (techniques used to advance action or create an effect; points of view; development of theme, characters, setting, plot)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Describe how a particular story’s or drama’s plot unfolds in a series of episodes as well as how the characters respond or change as the plot moves toward a resolution.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2643</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support opinions and ideas.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall information from experiences or gather information from print and digital sources; take brief notes on sources and sort evidence into provided categories.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2996</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Use explicit details and implicit information from texts to support inferences or analyses of the information presented</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2812</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Identify the reasons and evidence a speaker provides to support particular points.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2825</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the main ideas and supporting details of a text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2936</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYZE/INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Analyze information within and among sources of information (print and non-print texts, data sets, conducting procedures, etc.)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3184</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>5</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYSIS WITHIN OR ACROSS TEXTS: Analyze how information is presented showing relationships among literary elements within or across texts (dialogue, advancing action, character actions/interactions) or use of source material to develop literary elements</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze how particular elements of a story or drama interact (e.g., how setting shapes the characters or plot).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3171</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended, precise, or nuanced meanings of words, including words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word relationships, word structure (e.g., common Greek or Latin roots, affixes), or use of resources (e.g., dictionary, thesaurus, digital tools)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including figurative and connotative meanings; analyze the impact of rhymes and other repetitions of sounds (e.g., alliteration) on a specific verse or stanza of a poem or section of a story or drama.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3076</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the purpose of information presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and evaluate the motives (e.g., social, commercial, political) behind its presentation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3041</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply a variety of strategies when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of informational text: organizing ideas by stating and maintaining a focus/tone, developing a topic including relevant supporting evidence/ vocabulary and elaboration, or providing a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas, concepts, and information through the selection, organization, and analysis of relevant content. Develop the topic with relevant facts, definitions, concrete details, quotations, or other information and examples.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3680</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVALUATION: Apply reasoning and a range of textual evidence to justify inferences or judgments made (development of universal themes, characters; impact of point of view or discourse style (e.g., dramatic irony, humor, satire, understatement) on plot/subplot development</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the impact of the author’s choices regarding how to develop and relate elements of a story or drama (e.g., where a story is set, how the action is ordered, how the characters are introduced and developed).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3016</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>7</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Interpret figurative language use (e.g., personification, metaphor), literary devices, or connotative meanings of words and phrases used in context and their impact on reader interpretation</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including figurative and connotative meanings; analyze the impact of a specific word choice on meaning and tone.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2637</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support arguments, ideas, or analyses. </TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite several pieces of textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3105</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English capitalization, punctuation, and spelling when writing. A) Use punctuation (comma, ellipsis, dash) to indicate a pause or break.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3065</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the purpose of information presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and evaluate the motives (e.g., social, commercial, political) behind its presentation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2880</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Use explicit details and information from the text to support answers or basic inferences</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Ask and answer questions to demonstrate understanding of a text, referring explicitly to the text as the basis for the answers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3086</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support arguments or conjectures</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple authoritative print and digital sources, using advanced searches effectively; assess the strengths and limitations of each source in terms of the specific task, purpose, and audience; integrate information into the text selectively to maintain the flow of ideas, avoiding plagiarism and overreliance on any one source and following a standard format for citation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3038</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply a variety of strategies when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of text that express arguments about topics or texts: establishing and supporting a claim, organizing and citing supporting evidence using credible sources, appropriate vocabulary, or providing a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write arguments to support claims with clear reasons and relevant evidence. Support claim(s) with clear reasons and relevant evidence, using credible sources and demonstrating an understanding of the topic or text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2964</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English grammar and usage when writing or speaking. A) Ensure that pronouns are in the proper case (subjective, objective, possessive).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3129</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>7</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Determine or interpret impact or intent of figurative language/literary devices or connotative meanings of words and phrases used in context and the impact of those word choices on meaning and tone</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including figurative and connotative meanings; analyze the impact of specific word choices on meaning and tone, including analogies or allusions to other texts.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2638</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>COMPOSE FULL TEXTS: Write full explanatory texts using a complete writing process attending to purpose and audience: organize ideas by stating a thesis/controlling idea and maintaining a focus/tone; develop a topic including elaboration and citing relevant supporting evidence from sources, with appropriate transitional strategies for coherence; and develop a conclusion that is appropriate to purpose and audience and follows from and supports the information or explanation presented.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas, concepts, and information through the selection, organization, and analysis of relevant content. A) Introduce a topic clearly, previewing what is to follow; organize ideas, concepts, and information, using strategies such as definition, classification, comparison/contrast, and cause/ effect; include formatting (e.g., headings), graphics (e.g., charts, tables), and multimedia when useful to aiding comprehension.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>WER</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3684</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Summarize a written text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2645</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support opinions and ideas.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall information from experiences or gather information from print and digital sources; take brief notes on sources and sort evidence into provided categories.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2949</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Interpret information presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and explain how it contributes to a topic, text, or issue under study.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3035</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply narrative strategies (e.g., dialogue, description) and appropriate text structures and transitions when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of narrative text (e.g., introduce narrator or use dialogue when describing an event)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective technique, relevant descriptive details, and well-structured event sequences. Use narrative techniques, such as dialogue, pacing, and description, to develop experiences, events, and/or characters.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2667</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>COMPOSE FULL TEXTS: Write full informational texts on a topic using a complete writing process attending to purpose and audience: organize ideas by stating a focus (main idea); include text structures and appropriate transitional strategies for coherence; include elaboration and supporting evidence from sources; and develop an appropriate conclusion related to the information or explanation presented.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas and information clearly. Develop the topic with facts, definitions, concrete details, quotations, or other information and examples related to the topic. </CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>WER</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3052</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYZE/INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Analyze information within and among sources of information (print and non-print texts, data sets, conducting procedures, etc.)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare and contrast the information gained from experiments, simulations, video, or multimedia sources with that gained from reading a text on the same topic.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2635</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYZE/INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Analyze information within and among sources of information (print and non-print texts, data sets, conducting procedures, etc.).</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2946</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Interpret information presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and explain how it contributes to a topic, text, or issue under study.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2862</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the main ideas and supporting details of a text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3154</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>11</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVALUATION: Apply reasoning and a range of textual evidence to justify inferences or interpret author’s presentation of information (author’s line of reasoning, point of view/purpose support claims, concepts, ideas; relevance of evidence or elaboration to support claims)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Delineate and evaluate the argument and specific claims in a text, assessing whether the reasoning is sound and the evidence is relevant and sufficient; recognize when irrelevant evidence is introduced.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2895</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Identify or summarize central ideas/ key events</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a theme of a story, drama, or poem from details in the text; summarize the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3161</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>13</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES/ FEATURES: Relate knowledge of text structures or text features (e.g., graphics, bold text, headings) to obtain, interpret, or explain information</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Use text features and search tools (e.g., key words, sidebars, hyperlinks) to locate information relevant to a given topic efficiently.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3082</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Evaluate a speaker’s point of view, reasoning, and use of evidence and rhetoric, assessing the stance, premises, links among ideas, word choice, points of emphasis, and tone used.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3060</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYZE/INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Gather, analyze, and integrate multiple sources of information/evidence to support a presentation on a topic</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite specific textual evidence to support analysis of science and technical texts, attending to important distinctions the author makes and to any gaps or inconsistencies in the account.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2911</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Write or revise one or more paragraphs demonstrating specific narrative strategies (use of dialogue, sensory or concrete details, description), chronology, or authors’ craft appropriate to purpose (detailing characters, plot, setting, or an event)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective technique, descriptive details, and clear event sequences. Orient the reader by establishing a situation and introducing a narrator and/or characters; organize an event sequence that unfolds naturally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2698</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>7</Target>
		<TargetDesc>COMPOSE FULL TEXTS: Write full arguments about topics using the complete writing process: establish and support a claim; organize, elaborate, and cite supporting evidence from credible sources; provide appropriate transitional strategies for coherence; and develop a conclusion that is appropriate to purpose and audience and follows and supports the argument(s) presented.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write arguments to support claims with clear reasons and relevant evidence. Support claim(s) with logical reasoning and relevant evidence, using accurate, credible sources and demonstrating an understanding of the topic or text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>WER</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2841</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>10</Target>
		<TargetDesc>Determine intended or precise meanings of words, including domain-specific (tier 3) words and words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word relationships (e.g., antonyms, homographs), word structure (e.g., common Greek or Latin roots, affixes), or use of resources (e.g., dictionary, glossary)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of general academic and domain-specific words and phrases in a text relevant to a grade 5 topic or subject area.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2837</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Use explicit details and implicit information from texts to support answers or inferences about information presented</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Quote accurately from a text when explaining what the text says explicitly and when drawing inferences from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3006</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>11</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Use supporting evidence to justify interpretations or analyses of information presented or how information is integrated within a text (point of view; interactions among events, concepts, people, or ideas; author’s reasoning and evidence)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine an author’s point of view or purpose in a text and explain how it is conveyed in the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3139</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE &amp; VOCABULARY USE: Strategically use precise language and vocabulary (including academic words and domain-specific vocabulary figurative language,) and style appropriate to the purpose and audience when revising or composing texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas, concepts, and information through the selection, organization, and analysis of relevant content. D) Use precise language and domain-specific vocabulary to inform about or explain the topic.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3187</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>11</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Use supporting evidence to interpret and explain how information is presented or connected within or across texts (author’s point of view, ideas and supporting details, relationships)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Ask and answer questions to demonstrate understanding of a text, referring explicitly to the text as the basis for the answers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3113</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended, precise, or nuanced meanings of words, including words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word patterns, word relationships, word structure (e.g., common Greek or Latin roots, affixes), or use of resources (e.g., dictionary, thesaurus, digital tools)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine or clarify the meaning of unknown and multiple-meaning words or phrases based on grade 8 reading and content, choosing flexibly from a range of strategies. A) Use context (e.g., the overall meaning of a sentence or paragraph; a word’s position or function in a sentence) as a clue to the meaning of a word or phrase.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2818</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Write or revise one or more paragraphs demonstrating ability to organize ideas by stating a focus, including supporting evidence and elaboration, or writing body paragraphs or a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas and information clearly. B) Develop the topic with facts, definitions, and details.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2912</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Write or revise one or more paragraphs demonstrating ability to provide support for opinions about topics or texts: organize ideas by stating a context and focus, or develop supporting evidence /reasons and elaboration, or develop a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write opinion pieces on topics or texts, supporting a point of view with reasons. Introduce the topic or text they are writing about, state an opinion, and create an organizational structure that lists reasons.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2947</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Interpret information presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and explain how it contributes to a topic, text, or issue under study.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3008</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>11</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Use supporting evidence to justify interpretations or analyses of information presented or how information is integrated within a text (point of view; interactions among events, concepts, people, or ideas; author’s reasoning and evidence)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine an author’s point of view or purpose in a text and explain how it is conveyed in the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2816</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Write or revise one or more paragraphs demonstrating specific narrative strategies (use of dialogue, sensory or concrete details, description), chronology, or authors’ craft appropriate to purpose (detailing characters, plot, setting, or an event)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective technique, descriptive details, and clear event sequences. Use dialogue and descriptions of actions, thoughts, and feelings to develop experiences and events or show the response of characters to situations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3678</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>COMPOSE FULL TEXTS: Write longer narrative texts demonstrating narrative strategies, structures, transitions, and authors’ craft appropriate to purpose (writing a speech, developing point of view, style in short story)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective technique, relevant descriptive details, and well-structured event sequences. A) Engage and orient the reader by establishing a context and introducing a narrator and/or characters; organize an event sequence that unfolds naturally and logically.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>WER</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
		<Section>4</Section>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2874</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Generate conjectures or opinions and cite evidence to support them based on prior knowledge and evidence collected and analyzed</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research. </CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2644</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYZE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Distinguish relevant/irrelevant information.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall information from experiences or gather information from print and digital sources; take brief notes on sources and sort evidence into provided categories.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2647</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>INTERPRET/INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Locate information to support central ideas and subtopics that are provided; select and integrate information from data or print and non-print text source for a given purpose.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3173</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Apply reasoning and a range of textual evidence (e.g., quotes, examples, details) to justify analyses or judgments made</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze how particular elements of a story or drama interact (e.g., how setting shapes the characters or plot).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3145</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply narrative strategies (e.g., dialogue, description) and appropriate text structures and transitions when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of narrative text (e.g., introduce narrator or use dialogue when describing an event)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective technique, relevant descriptive details, and well-structured event sequences. Engage and orient the reader by establishing a context and point of view and introducing a narrator and/or characters; organize an event sequence that unfolds naturally and logically.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2893</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Use explicit details and implicit information from the text to support answers or basic inferences</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Refer to details and examples in a text when explaining what the text says explicitly and when drawing inferences from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3036</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply a variety of strategies when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of text that express arguments about topics or texts: establishing and supporting a claim, organizing and citing supporting evidence using credible sources, appropriate vocabulary, or providing a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas, concepts, and information through the selection, organization, and analysis of relevant content. Provide a concluding statement or section that follows from the information or explanation presented.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3677</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EVALUATE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Use reasoning, planning, and evidence to gather and select information to support inferences, interpretations, and analyses</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple print and digital sources; assess the credibility of each source; and quote or paraphrase the data and conclusions of others while avoiding plagiarism and providing basic bibliographic information for sources.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
		<Section>1</Section>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2697</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support arguments, ideas, or analyses.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2979</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYZE/INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Analyze information within and among sources of information (print and non-print texts, data sets, conducting procedures, etc.)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple print and digital sources; assess the credibility of each source; and quote or paraphrase the data and conclusions of others while avoiding plagiarism and providing basic bibliographic information for sources.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2835</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE &amp; VOCABULARY USE: Strategically use language and vocabulary (including academic or domain-specific vocabulary) appropriate to the purpose and audience when revising or composing texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas and information clearly. D) Use precise language and domain-specific vocabulary to inform about or explain the topic.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3127</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES/FEATURES: Relate knowledge of text structures or genre features (visual/graphic/auditory effects) to analyze the impact of those choices on meaning or presentation</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze in detail the structure of a specific paragraph in a text, including the role of particular sentences in developing and refining a key concept.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2930</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>5</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYSIS WITHIN OR ACROSS TEXTS: Interpret, specify, or compare how information is presented across texts (first-third person point of view, visual/oral formats, topics, themes, patterns of events)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Describe in depth a character, setting, or event in a story or drama, drawing on specific details in the text (e.g., a character’s thoughts, words, or actions).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2915</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>14</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Identify or interpret figurative language (e.g., metaphors, similes, idioms) use of literary devices or connotative meanings of words and phrases used in context</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate understanding of figurative language, word relationships, and nuances in word meanings.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3682</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Summarize a written text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2858</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>11</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVALUATION: Use supporting evidence to justify or interpret how information is presented or integrated (author’s reasoning, type of account, visual/graphic information, concepts, ideas)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Explain events, procedures, ideas, or concepts in a historical, scientific, or technical text, including what happened and why, based on specific information in the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2849</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the main ideas and supporting details of a text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2916</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>12</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYSIS WITHIN OR ACROSS TEXTS: Interpret, explain, or connect information presented within or across texts (e.g., compare-contrast, show cause-effect, integrate information)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Refer to details and examples in a text when explaining what the text says explicitly and when drawing inferences from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2954</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Summarize a written text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2960</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>6</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Write or revise one or more paragraphs demonstrating ability to provide support for opinions about topics or texts: organize ideas by stating a context and focus, or develop supporting evidence /reasons and elaboration, or develop a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write opinion pieces on topics or texts, supporting a point of view with reasons and information. Provide a concluding statement or section related to the opinion presented.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2899</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVALUATION: Use supporting evidence to justify/ explain inferences (character development/actions/traits; first or third person point of view; theme; author’s message)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Describe in depth a character, setting, or event in a story or drama, drawing on specific details in the text (e.g., a character’s thoughts, words, or actions).</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2847</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>13</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES &amp; FEATURES: Relate knowledge of text structures to compare or connect information across texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare and contrast the overall structure (e.g., chronology, comparison, cause/effect, problem/solution) of events, ideas, concepts, or information in two or more texts.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2828</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Identify the reasons and evidence a speaker provides to support particular points.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>EBSR</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2882</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Use explicit details and information from the text to support answers or basic inferences</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Ask and answer questions to demonstrate understanding of a text, referring explicitly to the text as the basis for the answers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2934</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EVALUATE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Use reasoning, planning, and evidence to gather and select information to support inferences, interpretations, and analyses</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Gather relevant information from multiple print and digital sources, using search terms effectively; assess the credibility and accuracy of each source; and quote or paraphrase the data and conclusions of others while avoiding plagiarism and following a standard format for citation.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2975</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Interpret information presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and explain how it contributes to a topic, text, or issue under study.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3072</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Delineate a speaker’s argument and specific claims, evaluating the soundness of the reasoning and relevance and sufficiency of the evidence and identifying when irrelevant evidence is introduced.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2854</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Identify or summarize central ideas, key events, or procedures</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the main idea of a text and explain how it is supported by key details; summarize the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2823</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Write or revise one or more paragraphs demonstrating specific narrative strategies (use of dialogue, sensory or concrete details, description), chronology, or authors’ craft appropriate to purpose (detailing characters, plot, setting, or an event)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective technique, descriptive details, and clear event sequences. Use dialogue and description to develop experiences and events or show the responses of characters to situations.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3099</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended, precise, or nuanced meanings of words, including distinguishing connotation-denotation and words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word patterns, word relationships, etymology, or use of specialized resources (e.g., dictionary, thesaurus, digital tools</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in the text, including figurative and connotative meanings; analyze the impact of specific word choices on meaning and tone, including words with multiple meanings or language that is particularly fresh, engaging, or beautiful. (Include Shakespeare as well as other authors.)</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3149</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WRITE/REVISE BRIEF TEXTS: Apply a variety of strategies when writing or revising one or more paragraphs of informational texts: organizing ideas by stating a thesis and maintaining a focus, developing a complex topic/subtopics, including relevant supporting evidence (from texts when appropriate) and elaboration, or providing a conclusion appropriate to purpose and audience</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine and convey complex ideas, concepts, and information clearly and accurately through the effective selection, organization, and analysis of content.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3163</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Use explicit details and implicit information from the text to support answers or inferences about information presented.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Ask and answer questions to demonstrate understanding of a text, referring explicitly to the text as the basis for the answers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2956</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Summarize a written text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2952</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Interpret and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Summarize a written text read aloud or information presented in diverse media and formats, including visually, quantitatively, and orally.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2851</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Use explicit details and implicit information from the text to support answers or basic inferences about information presented</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Refer to details and examples in a text when explaining what the text says explicitly and when drawing inferences from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3177</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 3</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>11</Target>
		<TargetDesc>REASONING &amp; EVIDENCE: Use supporting evidence to interpret and explain how information is presented or connected within or across texts (author’s point of view, ideas and supporting details, relationships)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Ask and answer questions to demonstrate understanding of a text, referring explicitly to the text as the basis for the answers.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3102</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Cite explicit text evidence to support inferences made or conclusions drawn about texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite strong and thorough textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text, including determining where the text leaves matters uncertain.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2695</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYZE/INTEGRATE INFORMATION: Analyze information within and among sources of information (print and non-print texts, data sets, conducting procedures, etc.).</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3002</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE &amp; VOCABULARY USE: Strategically use precise language and vocabulary (including academic words and domain-specific vocabulary figurative language,) and style appropriate to the purpose and audience when revising or composing texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write informative/explanatory texts to examine a topic and convey ideas, concepts, and information through the selection, organization, and analysis of relevant content. D) Use precise language and domain-specific vocabulary to inform about or explain the topic.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3165</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>7</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE USE: Interpret impact or intent of figurative language use (e.g., alliteration, onomatopoeia, imagery), literary devices (e.g., flashback, foreshadowing), or connotative meanings of words and phrases used in context and their impact on reader interpretation</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including figurative and connotative meanings; analyze the impact of rhymes and other repetitions of sounds (e.g., alliteration) on a specific verse or stanza of a poem or section of a story or drama.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2972</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the main ideas and supporting details presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and explain how the ideas clarify a topic, text, or issue under study.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2665</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>ANALYZE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Distinguish relevant/irrelevant information.</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall relevant information from experiences or gather relevant information from print and digital sources; take notes and categorize information, and provide a list of sources.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>4</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2868</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>WORD MEANINGS: Determine intended or precise meanings of words, including words with multiple meanings (academic/tier 2 words), based on context, word relationships (e.g., antonyms, homographs), word structure (e.g., common Greek or Latin roots, affixes), or use of resources (e.g., dictionary, thesaurus)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine the meaning of words and phrases as they are used in a text, including figurative language such as metaphors and similes.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3018</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 6</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Use explicit details and implicit information from the text to support inferences or analyses of the information presented</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Cite textual evidence to support analysis of what the text says explicitly as well as inferences drawn from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2982</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 7</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Analyze the main ideas and supporting details presented in diverse media and formats (e.g., visually, quantitatively, orally) and explain how the ideas clarify a topic, text, or issue under study.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2938</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>8</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LANGUAGE &amp; VOCABULARY USE: Strategically use language and vocabulary (including academic or domain-specific vocabulary) appropriate to the purpose and audience when revising or composing texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Write narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective technique, descriptive details, and clear event sequences. D) Use concrete words and phrases and sensory details to convey experiences and events precisely.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2879</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>1</Target>
		<TargetDesc>KEY DETAILS: Use explicit details and implicit information from the text to support answers or inferences about information</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Quote accurately from a text when explaining what the text says explicitly and when drawing inferences from the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2951</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA2</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EDIT/CLARIFY: Apply or edit grade-appropriate grammar usage and mechanics to clarify a message and edit narrative, informational, and persuasive/opinion texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Demonstrate command of the conventions of standard English grammar and usage when writing or speaking. B) Form and use the perfect (e.g., I had walked; I have walked; I will have walked) verb tenses.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>HTQ</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3078</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA3</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>LISTEN/INTERPRET: Analyze, interpret, and use information delivered orally or visually</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Evaluate a speaker’s point of view, reasoning, and use of evidence and rhetoric, assessing the stance, premises, links among ideas, word choice, points of emphasis, and tone used.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>1</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3063</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 8</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>4</Target>
		<TargetDesc>USE EVIDENCE: Cite evidence to support analyses, arguments, or critiques</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Draw evidence from literary or informational texts to support analysis, reflection, and research.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MI</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>3090</ItemId>
		<Grade>High School</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>9</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Summarize central ideas, topics/subtopics, key events, or procedures using supporting ideas and relevant details</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine two or more central ideas of a text and analyze their development over the course of the text, including how they interact and build on one another to provide a complex analysis; provide an objective summary of the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>SA</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>3</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2870</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>2</Target>
		<TargetDesc>CENTRAL IDEAS: Identify or summarize central ideas/ key events</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Determine a theme of a story, drama, or poem from details in the text, including how characters in a story or drama respond to challenges or how the speaker in a poem reflects upon a topic; summarize the text.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2845</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 5</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA1</Claim>
		<Target>13</Target>
		<TargetDesc>TEXT STRUCTURES &amp; FEATURES: Relate knowledge of text structures to compare or connect information across texts</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Compare and contrast the overall structure (e.g., chronology, comparison, cause/effect, problem/solution) of events, ideas, concepts, or information in two or more texts.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MC</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
	<row>
		<ItemId>2928</ItemId>
		<Grade>Grade 4</Grade>
		<Claim>ELA4</Claim>
		<Target>3</Target>
		<TargetDesc>EVALUATE INFORMATION/SOURCES: Distinguish relevant-irrelevant information (e.g., fact/opinion)</TargetDesc>
		<CCSSDesc>Recall relevant information from experiences or gather relevant information from print and digital sources; take notes and categorize information, and provide a list of sources.</CCSSDesc>
		<ItemType>MS</ItemType>
		<DepthOfKnowledge>2</DepthOfKnowledge>
	</row>
</root>